So welcome to the Machine [NOISE] Translation lecture,
欢迎来到机器[NOISE]翻译讲座，
which is kind of like a culmination [NOISE] of
这有点像一个高潮[NOISE]
this sequence of three lectures on RNNs and related topics.
关于RNN和相关主题的三个讲座的序列。
So let's have a few announcements first.
所以我们首先要发布一些声明。
Uh, the first thing is,
呃，首先是，
as you probably noticed when you came in,
当你进来时你可能已经注意到
we're taking attendance today.
我们今天正在参加。
Uh, so you need to sign in with the TAs who are outside the auditorium.
呃，所以你需要在礼堂外签名。
Uh, if you missed it,
呃，如果你错过了，
don't get up now, it's fine.
现在不起床，没关系。
There will be time to sign in after the lecture.
讲座后有时间登录。
Uh, and then, if you have any kind of questions about
呃，然后，如果你有任何问题
special cases with the attendance policy, uh,
出勤政策的特殊情况，呃，
you should check out a Piazza post that we put up last night with some clarifications.
你应该查看我们昨晚提出的一个广场帖子，并做了一些澄清。
[NOISE] Uh, you have the reminder that Assignment 4 content is going to be covered today.
[NOISE]呃，你有提醒说今天将分配作业4的内容。
So you're gonna have everything you need to do Assignment 4 at the end of today.
因此，您将拥有在今天结束时完成作业4所需的一切。
[NOISE] And do get started early because the model takes 4 hours to train.
[噪音]并提前开始，因为该模型需要4个小时的训练。
The other announcement is that we're going [NOISE] to be sending out
另一个公告是我们要[发送] [发送]
our mid-quarter feedback survey sometime in the next few days probably,
我们可能会在接下来几天的某个时候进行中期反馈调查，
uh, so please do fill it out.
呃，所以请填写。
You'll get 0,5% credit,
你将获得0,5％的学分，
and you're also gonna help us to make the class better for the rest of the quarter.
而你也将帮助我们在本季剩余时间里让课程变得更好。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So here's the overview of what we're going to do today.
所以这里是我们今天要做的事情的概述。
[NOISE] Uh, today, first,
[NOISE]呃，今天，第一，
we're going to introduce a new task in NLP,
我们将在NLP中介绍一项新任务，
which is machine translation, [NOISE] and then,
这是机器翻译，[NOISE]然后，
we're going to introduce a new neural architecture called sequence-to-sequence.
我们将介绍一种称为序列到序列的新神经结构。
And the connection here is that machine translation
这里的连接就是机器翻译
is a major use case of sequence-to-sequence.
是序列到序列的主要用例。
[NOISE] After that, we're going to introduce a new neural technique called attention,
[NOISE]在那之后，我们将介绍一种名为注意力的新神经技术，
and this is something that improves sequence-to-sequence a lot.
这是一个可以改进序列到序列的东西。
Okay. So Section 1 of this is gonna be about, uh,
好的。因此，第1节将是关于，呃，
a bit of machine translation history, pre-neural machine translation.
一点机器翻译历史，预神经机器翻译。
[NOISE] So machine translation or MT,
[NOISE]所以机器翻译或MT，
uh, is the task of translating a sentence x, uh,
呃，是翻译句子的任务x，呃，
which we call the source language,
我们称之为源语言，
whatever language you're translating from,
无论你翻译什么语言，
into a sentence y, which is in another language,
换句话y，用另一种语言，
which we call the target language.
我们称之为目标语言。
Uh, so here's an example. Let's suppose x is this French sentence.
呃，这是一个例子。我们假设x是这个法语句子。
Um, [NOISE] could anyone in the audience,
嗯，[NOISE]观众中的任何人都可以，
a French speaker, translate this to English for us? [NOISE] [BACKGROUND] Yeah.
一位法语发言人，为我们翻译成英语？ [NOISE] [背景]是的。
Um, the man is born free, and, uh, everywhere, he is in irons.
嗯，这个人天生就是自由的，呃，无处不在，他都是铁杆。
Great.
大。
So that was something like,
这就是这样的，
the man is born free, but everywhere, he's in irons.
这个人天生就是自由的，但无处不在，他都是铁杆。
That was a fairly literal translation.
这是一个相当字面的翻译。
It's usually translated, this quote by Rousseau is usually translated as,
它通常被翻译，卢梭的这句话通常翻译为，
man is born free, but everywhere, he is in chains.
男人天生自由，但无处不在，他是枷锁。
But there's an ambiguity: [NOISE] should fers be,
但是有一种含糊之处：[NOISE]应该是，
um, literally irons or chains?
嗯，字面上是铁杆还是链子？
Also, you could choose to, uh,
另外，你可以选择，呃，
translate l'homme as man or maybe humankind.
将l'homme翻译为男人或人类。
Uh, so this is an example of machine translation,
呃，这是机器翻译的一个例子，
and there's already, you know,
你知道，已经有了
quite a few choices you can make.
你可以做出很多选择。
[NOISE] So the beginning of machine translation as an AI task began in the early 1950s.
[NOISE]因此，作为AI任务的机器翻译的开始始于20世纪50年代初。
So, um, in particular,
所以，嗯，特别是，
there was a lot of work translating Russian to English, uh,
有很多工作将俄语翻译成英语，呃，
because the West was very interested in listening
因为西方对听力很感兴趣
to what the Russians were saying during the Cold War.
俄罗斯人在冷战期间所说的话。
And we've got a fun video here,
我们这里有一个有趣的视频，
[NOISE] which shows the state of machine translation in 1954.
[NOISE]显示1954年的机器翻译状态。
[MUSIC] They haven't reckoned with
[音乐]他们没有考虑到
ambiguity when they set out to use computers to translate languages.
他们开始使用计算机翻译语言时含糊不清。
A $500,000 simple calculator,
500,000美元的简单计算器，
most versatile electronic brain known,
最通用的电子脑已知，
translates Russian into English.
将俄语翻译成英语。
Instead of mathematical wizardry,
而不是数学魔法，
a sentence in Russian is to be fed [OVERLAPPING].
用俄语写一个句子[OVERLAPPING]。
One of the first non-numerical applications of computers,
计算机的第一个非数字应用之一，
[BACKGROUND] it was hyped as the solution to
[背景]它被大肆宣传为解决方案
the Cold War obsession of keeping tabs on what the Russians were doing.
冷战痴迷于密切关注俄罗斯人正在做什么。
Claims were made that the computer would replace most human translators.
声称计算机将取代大多数人工翻译。
[inaudible] you're just in the experimental stage.
[听不清]你刚刚进入实验阶段。
When you go in for full-scale production,
当你进行全面生产时，
what will the capacity be?
容量是多少？
We should be able to do about,
我们应该能够做到，
with the help of a commercial computer, uh, about one to two million words, uh,
在商业电脑的帮助下，呃，大约一两百万字，呃，
an hour, and this will be quite an adequate speed to cope with
一个小时，这将是一个足够的速度来应对
the whole alphabet of the Soviet Union in just a few hours' computer time a week.
苏联的整个字母表，每周只需几个小时的计算机时间。
When do you have to be able to achieve this feat?
你何时必须能够实现这一壮举？
If our experiments go well,
如果我们的实验进展顺利，
then perhaps within, uh, five years or so.
然后也许在，呃，五年左右。
So in this video, I think there's a number of interesting things.
所以在这个视频中，我认为有很多有趣的事情。
Uh, firstly, we can see an example of about how,
呃，首先，我们可以看到一个关于如何的例子，
uh, AI hype is nothing new.
呃，AI炒作并不是什么新鲜事。
Even in 1954, [NOISE] they were talking
甚至在1954年，[NOISE]他们正在谈论
this machine translation system as if it was an electronic brain,
这台机器翻译系统仿佛它是一个电子大脑，
which I think, uh, overstates maybe how general it is.
我认为，呃，夸大其概率。
Uh, they were also, at least some of them,
呃，他们也是，至少其中一些，
fairly optimistic that this [NOISE] machine translation system
相当乐观的是[NOISE]机器翻译系统
was going to be replacing humans, uh, anytime soon.
很快就会取代人类，呃。
Um, so yeah, that's, that's pretty interesting.
嗯，所以是的，那是非常有趣的。
And, um, [NOISE] the thing is that these systems actually were mostly rule-based, uh,
而且，嗯，[NOISE]问题是这些系统实际上主要是基于规则的，呃，
by which I mean that they were mostly using
我的意思是他们大多使用
a bilingual dictionary between Russian and English,
俄语和英语之间的双语词典，
and they were essentially mostly just looking up the Russian words, uh,
他们基本上只是查找俄语单词，呃，
looking up their English counterparts,
抬头看他们的英文同行，
and they were storing these big bilingual dictionaries on these large magnetic tapes.
他们将这些大型双语词典存放在这些大磁带上。
Um, so certainly, it was a [NOISE] huge technical feat at the time, uh,
嗯，当然，那是一个[NOISE]巨大的技术壮举，呃，
but they, uh, some people were probably too
但他们，呃，有些人可能也是
optimistic [NOISE] about how quickly it would replace humans.
关于它将如何快速取代人类的乐观[NOISE]。
So jumping forward several decades in time,
所以几十年前后，
uh, now I want to tell you about statistical machine translation.
呃，现在我想告诉你关于统计机器的翻译。
So the core idea of statistical machine translation is that you're going to
所以统计机器翻译的核心思想就是你要去的
learn a probabilistic model from the data in order to do the translation.
从数据中学习概率模型以进行翻译。
So as an example, uh, as before,
举个例子，呃，和以前一样，
suppose that we're translating from French to English.
假设我们正在从法语翻译成英语。
The idea is that you want to find the best English sentence y,
想法是你想找到最好的英语句子y，
given the French sentence x,
鉴于法语句子x，
[NOISE] and, uh, mathematically,
[NOISE]而且，呃，在数学上，
you can formulate this as finding argmax y of this conditional probability of y, given x,
你可以将此表示为找到y的这个条件概率的argmax y，给定x，
[NOISE] and the model that you're learning is
[NOISE]和你正在学习的模型是
this probability distribution P. [NOISE] So what we usually do is,
这个概率分布P. [NOISE]所以我们通常做的是，
we break down this probability into,
我们把这个概率分解成，
uh, its two components using Bayes' Rule.
呃，它的两个组成部分使用贝叶斯规则。
[NOISE] So this means that finding the y that maximizes,
[NOISE]所以这意味着找到最大化的y，
uh, probability of y, given x,
呃，y的概率，给定x，
is equivalent to finding the y that maximizes the probability of x,
相当于找到最大化x概率的y，
given y, times the probability of y.
给定y乘以y的概率。
So the two components here, on the left,
所以这两个组件在左边，
we have a translation model,
我们有翻译模型，
and this is keeping track of how words and phrases should be translated.
这是跟踪单词和短语应该如何翻译。
Uh, so the idea is that it knows, uh, how, uh,
呃，所以这个想法是它知道，呃，怎么样，呃，
French words and an English word might be translated to each other or maybe small,
法语单词和英语单词可能相互翻译或者可能很小，
small phrases and chunks of words should be translated.
应该翻译小词和大块的单词。
And this is learned from a lot of parallel data,
这是从很多并行数据中学到的，
and I'll be telling you later how we do that.
我稍后会告诉你我们是怎么做到的。
The second compo- component P(y),
第二个组分P（y），
[NOISE] this is just a language model.
[NOISE]这只是一种语言模型。
[NOISE] We learned about this last week.
[噪音]上周我们了解到了这一点。
A language model is a system that can predict the next word,
语言模型是一个可以预测下一个单词的系统，
but it can also be thought of as a system [NOISE] that tells
但它也可以被认为是一个告诉你的系统[NOISE]
you the probability of a sequence of words.
你是一系列单词的概率。
So here, if we're translating from French to English,
所以在这里，如果我们从法语翻译成英语，
P(y) is an English language model.
P（y）是英语语言模型。
[NOISE] So the idea is the,
[NOISE]所以这个想法是，
the reason why we want to break down
我们想要打破的原因
this single conditiona- conditional probability distribution into the,
这条单一条件 - 条件概率分布到，
the pr- product of two different ones is that this is a kind of division of labor.
两种不同的产品是这是一种分工。
The idea is that instead of, uh,
这个想法是，而不是，呃，
a single conditional probability distribution needing to understand how to translate,
单个条件概率分布需要理解如何翻译，
and how to write good English text,
以及如何写出好的英文文本，
and understand sentence structure,
并理解句子结构，
and everything at once, the idea is that you separate it so that [NOISE]
而且一下子，你的想法就是把它分开以便[NOISE]
the translation model on the left in blue mostly just knows about a
蓝色左边的翻译模型大多只知道一个
local translation of small chunks of words and phrases,
小块单词和短语的本地翻译，
whereas the language model on the right more takes care of writing good English,
而右边的语言模型更注重写好英语，
good sentence structure, word order, and so on.
良好的句子结构，词序等。
[NOISE] So you already know
[NOISE]所以你已经知道了
how to learn a language model [NOISE] because we learned about that last time.
如何学习语言模型[NOISE]因为我们最后一次学到了这一点。
You just need lots of monolingual data,
你只需要很多单语数据，
in this case, English data.
在这种情况下，英文数据。
[NOISE] So I'm going to tell you more about how we would learn
[NOISE]所以我要告诉你更多关于我们将如何学习的内容
this translation model that needs to be learned from parallel data.
这个需要从并行数据中学习的翻译模型。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
So we need a large amount of parallel data in order to learn this translation model.
因此，我们需要大量的并行数据才能学习这种翻译模型。
And an early example of a parallel corpus,
并行语料库的早期例子，
is the Rosetta Stone.
是罗塞塔石碑。
So this is a stone that has the same text written in three different languages.
所以这是一块用三种不同语言写成相同文本的石头。
And this is a hugely important artifact
这是一件非常重要的神器
for the people who were trying to understand ancient Egyptian.
对于那些试图了解古埃及人的人。
So in the 19th century,
所以在19世纪，
uh, scholars discovered this stone,
呃，学者发现了这块石头，
and it helped them to figure out ancient Egyptian because there was
它帮助他们找出古埃及人，因为有
this parallel text that had the the same text in other languages that they did know.
这个并行文本在他们知道的其他语言中具有相同的文本。
So this is, this is a really important parallel corpus,
所以这就是，这是一个非常重要的平行语料库，
and if you're ever in London,
如果你曾经在伦敦，
you can go to the British Museum,
你可以去大英博物馆，
and see this in person.
并亲自看到这个。
So the idea is that you get your parallel data.
所以我们的想法是获得并行数据。
Obviously, you need a larger amount that is on the stone,
显然，你需要更多的石头，
and hopefully it shouldn't be written on a stone either.
并且希望它也不应该写在石头上。
But you can use this to learn your statistical machine translation model.
但您可以使用它来学习统计机器翻译模型。
So the idea is that, you are trying to learn
所以我的想法是，你正在努力学习
this conditional probability distribution of x given y.
给定y的x的条件概率分布。
So what we do is we actually break this down even further.
所以我们做的是我们实际上进一步打破了这一点。
We actually want to consider the probability of x and a given y.
我们实际上想要考虑x和给定y的概率。
Where a is the alignment.
其中a是对齐方式。
So the idea of alignment,
所以对齐的想法，
is this is how the words in
这是怎么回事
the English sentence and the French sentence correspond to each other.
英语句子和法语句子相互对应。
So I'm gonna, uh, demonstrate this by an example.
所以我要通过一个例子证明这一点。
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中，
while we're translating the sentence 'Japan shaken by two new quakes' to French.
而我们正在将“日本因两次新地震而动摇”的句子翻译成法语。
Then you can see there is a pretty simple one-to-one alignment here,
然后你可以看到这里有一个非常简单的一对一对齐，
uh, of English words to French words,
呃，英语单词到法语单词，
and also they appear in the exact same order.
它们也以完全相同的顺序出现。
The only thing that doesn't conform to that is the word 'Le' in French,
唯一不符合这一点的是法语中的'Le'这个词，
which we call a spurious word because it doesn't
我们称之为虚假词，因为它没有
have a direct counterpart in the English sentence,
在英文句子中有一个直接的对应物，
and that's because in English we just say,
那是因为在英语中我们只是说，
'Japan', but in French we say, 'Le Japon'.
'日本'，但用法语我们说'Le Japon'。
So alignment can be a bit more complicated than that.
因此，对齐可能比这更复杂。
For example, alignment can be many-to-one.
例如，对齐可以是多对一的。
In this example, you have, uh,
在这个例子中，你有，呃，
several French words that have multiple English words that correspond to them.
几个法语单词，有多个与之对应的英语单词。
So this is what we call many-to-one alignment.
所以这就是我们所谓的多对一对齐。
Uh, it can go in the other direction too.
呃，它也可以向另一个方向发展。
Alignment can be one-to-many.
对齐可以是一对多。
So here we have a single English word implemented,
所以这里我们实现了一个单词，
which has a one-to-many alignment because there is
它有一对多的对齐，因为有
a three-word French phra-phrase that corresponds to it.
与之相对应的三字法语词组。
So on the left and the right,
所以在左边和右边，
we have two ways of depicting the same alignments.
我们有两种描绘相同路线的方法。
It's either a kind of chart or it can be a, a graph.
它可以是一种图表，也可以是图表。
So here's another example, um,
所以这是另一个例子，嗯，
of a one-to-many, well, sorry, right.
一对多，好吧，抱歉，对。
So we call, uh, this word implemented, that is one-to-many.
所以我们称之为，呃，实施了这个词，即一对多。
We call it a fertile word because the idea is that it has many children in the,
我们称之为一个肥沃的词，因为这个想法是它有许多孩子，
in the target sentence.
在目标句子中。
So in fact, there are some words which are very fertile.
事实上，有些词语非常肥沃。
Here's an example where the source sentence,
这是一个源句子的例子，
'il m'a entarte', means,
'il m'a entarte'，意思是，
'he hit me with a pie',
“他用馅饼打我”，
and here in French,
这里用法语，
this verb, 'entarte' means, uh, to hit someone with a pie,
这个动词，'entarte'意思是，呃，用饼来打人，
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
and this word has no single word equivalent in English.
这个词在英语中没有相同的单词。
We don't have a single verb that means to hit someone with a pie.
我们没有单一的动词，意味着用馅饼打人。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Which I think that is really fun, that French has a word.
我认为这真的很有趣，法语有一个词。
You wonder, maybe they do it so
你想知道，也许他们这样做了
often that they need a single word for that. I don't know.
通常，他们需要一个单词。我不知道。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
So this is an example of a fertile word, right?
所以这是一个肥沃的词的例子，对吧？
Because it needs to have several corresponding English words to translate it.
因为它需要有几个相应的英文单词来翻译它。
So we can have one-to-many, and many-to-one.
所以我们可以有一对多，多对一。
You can also have many-to-many alignments.
您还可以进行多对多对齐。
You could call that kind of phrase level translation, or phrase-to-phrase.
您可以将这种短语级别翻译或短语转换为短语。
So here, uh, the English sentence says,
所以在这里，呃，英文句子说，
'The poor doesn't- don't have any money',
“穷人没有 - 没有钱”，
and here don't have any money corresponds to the French phrase,
这里没有任何钱对应法语短语，
'sont demunis', and this is a many-to-many alignment because there is
'sont demunis'，这是一个多对多的对齐，因为有
no obvious way to break down this phrase-to-phrase alignment into,
没有明显的方法来打破这种短语到短语的对齐，
um, smaller word-to-word alignments.
嗯，较小的单词对齐。
Okay. So that's what alignment is.
好的。这就是对齐方式。
And if you remember, we were thinking about how would you
如果你还记得，我们在想你会怎样
learn this probability distribution of what the alignment is,
学习这种对齐方式的概率分布，
uh, in order to do statistical machine translation.
呃，为了做统计机器翻译。
So the idea is that you learn probability of x and a,
所以我的想法是你学习x和a的概率，
given y as a combination of many factors or many features.
将y视为许多因素或许多特征的组合。
So you consider for example,
所以你考虑一下，例如，
what's the probability of a particular word aligning to another particular word?
特定单词与另一个特定单词对齐的概率是多少？
Like you know, this English word and this French word,
就像你知道的，这个英文单词和这个法语单词，
how often do they align?
他们经常对齐？
But then, this also depends on for example,
但是，这也取决于例如，
what's their position in the sentence?
他们在句子中的立场是什么？
Like if they both appear near the end of the sentences,
就好如果它们都出现在句子的末尾附近，
then it's more likely that they align, whereas,
那么它们更可能是对齐的，而
if one's at the beginning and one's at the end, that's less likely.
如果一个人在开始时和一个人在最后，那就不太可能了。
You would also consider things like, uh,
你也会考虑这样的事情，呃，
what's the probability of this particular French word having this particular fertility?
这个特殊的法语单词具有这种特殊生育能力的概率是多少？
Like, what's the probability of this word having
比如，这个词的概率是多少
three corresponding English words and so on?
三个相应的英文单词等？
So all of these statistics are learned from your parallel data,
所以这些统计数据都是从你的并行数据中学到的，
and there's many other things that you would take into consideration.
还有很多其他事情需要考虑。
So we're looking at a kind of overview of statistical machine translation today.
所以我们今天看一下统计机器翻译的概述。
You're not going to understand it in full detail,
你不会详细了解它，
but we're understanding an overview of how it works,
但我们理解它是如何工作的概述，
because we're going to be, uh,
因为我们会成为，呃，
comparing it to neural machine translation.
将其与神经机器翻译进行比较。
Okay. So we're learning this SMT system,
好的。所以我们正在学习这个SMT系统，
and so far, we've broken it down into these two main components.
到目前为止，我们已将其分解为这两个主要组成部分。
We've got the translation model,
我们有翻译模型，
and we've got the language model,
我们有语言模型，
and we understand a little bit about how you might
我们对你的理解有所了解
learn this translation model by breaking it down into alignments.
通过将其分解为对齐来学习此翻译模型。
So the question remains, how do you do the argmax over y?
所以问题仍然存在，你怎么做argmax超过y？
How do you find your French sentence y that maximizes this probability?
你如何找到最大化这个概率的法语句子？
So one kind of brute force solution is you could say,
所以你可以说，有一种蛮力解决方案，
"'let's enumerate every possible y."
“'让我们列举一切可能的y。”
That's kind of every possible sequence of French words,
这就是法语单词的每一个可能序列，
maybe up to some length, and, uh,
可能达到一定的长度，呃，
we'll calculate this probability for all of them,
我们将计算所有这些概率，
and it should be pretty clear that that is just a no go.
而且应该很清楚，这只是不行。
That's way too expensive,
那太贵了，
and we're not going to be able to get anywhere with that.
而且我们无法在任何地方找到它。
So the answer for how you actually do this in practice is,
那么你在实践中如何实际做到这一点的答案是，
you are going to use some kind of heuristic search algorithm,
你将使用某种启发式搜索算法，
to search for the best translation, y.
搜索最佳翻译，y。
Uh, but along the way, you're going to discard hypotheses that are too low probability.
呃，但在此过程中，你要放弃概率太低的假设。
So you're gonna search,
所以你要搜索，
you're going to discard,
你要丢弃，
and prune the trees as you go to make sure that you're not
并且在你去的时候修剪树木，以确保你不是
keeping too many hypotheses, uh, on each step.
保持太多假设，呃，每一步。
So this process of finding your best sequence is also called decoding.
因此，找到最佳序列的过程也称为解码。
So here is an overview of how that works for SMT.
因此，这里概述了SMT的工作原理。
This an example where you have this German sentence that translates to,
这个例子中你有这个德语句子翻译成，
'He does not go home',
'他不回家'，
and you can see that there is some kind of phrase-to-phrase alignment here.
你可以看到这里有一些短语到短语的对齐方式。
So, uh, an overview of how this decoding would work in SMT,
所以，呃，概述了这种解码在SMT中的作用，
is that you kind of consider lots of different hypotheses,
是你有点考虑很多不同的假设，
for how you might translate these individual words, uh,
你怎么翻译这些单词，呃，
and then you build it up to consider how you might translate,
然后你构建它来考虑你可以如何翻译，
uh, individual phrases, and the phrases get bigger.
呃，个别短语和短语变得更大。
So for example, you can see that on the top right,
例如，您可以在右上方看到
if it's not too small, you can see that the, uh,
如果它不是太小，你可以看到，呃，
the German word for house, uh,
德语单词for house，呃，
could be translated into the English word,
可以翻译成英文单词，
'house' or 'home', or 'chamber', and so on.
'house'或'home'，或'chamber'，等等。
Uh, so we consider all of these different hypotheses,
呃，所以我们考虑所有这些不同的假设，
and look into how we might put those together to
并研究我们如何把它们放在一起
translate phrases but you don't keep all of them all the time.
翻译短语，但你不会一直保留所有这些短语。
You get rid of the ones that are too low probability.
你摆脱了概率太低的那些。
So this can also be depicted as a kind of a tree,
所以这也可以描述为一种树，
where you are exploring different options.
你在哪里探索不同的选择。
You are searching through the space of options,
您正在搜索选项空间，
but then you prune the tree as you go.
但随后你去修剪树。
So I know this is a very,
所以我知道这是一个非常的，
very high level, uh,
非常高的，呃，
description of how decoding might walk.
解码如何走的描述。
And in fact, later in this lecture,
事实上，在本讲座的后期，
you're going to see a detailed explanation
你会看到一个详细的解释
of how this kind of decoding works for neural machine translation.
这种解码如何用于神经机器翻译。
Okay. So what's our, um,
好的。那么我们是什么，嗯，
overview of statistical machine translation,
统计机器翻译概述，
uh, was it effective?
呃，它有效吗？
Uh, so SMT was a huge research field,
呃，所以SMT是一个巨大的研究领域，
uh, from the 1990s to about, maybe, uh, 2013.
呃，从20世纪90年代到约，也许，呃，2013年。
And the best systems during this time were extremely complex.
在此期间，最好的系统非常复杂。
They were extremely sophisticated and impressive systems and, uh,
他们是非常复杂和令人印象深刻的系统，呃，
SMT made the best machine translation systems in the world.
SMT成为世界上最好的机器翻译系统。
But they were very complex.
但它们非常复杂。
So for example, you know,
例如，你知道，
there were hundreds of important details that we haven't mentioned here at all.
我们在这里根本没有提到数百个重要细节。
There were many, many techniques to make it, uh,
有很多很多技术可以做到，呃，
more complex and more,
更复杂，更多，
um, sophisticated than what I've described today.
嗯，比我今天描述的要复杂。
In particular, the systems had to have many separately designed, uh, sub-components.
特别是，系统必须具有许多单独设计的子组件。
So we already saw how you, uh,
所以我们已经看到了你，呃，
break down the translation model into two separate parts.
将翻译模型分解为两个独立的部分。
Uh, but there was, you know, many more sub-components than that,
呃，但是，你知道，还有更多的子组件，
and often they had to be learned separately.
通常他们必须分开学习。
This meant the engineers had to do a lot of feature engineering.
这意味着工程师必须进行大量的功能工程。
Uh, you have to design features to capture
呃，你必须设计要捕捉的功能
the particular language phenomena that you were interested in.
您感兴趣的特定语言现象。
So this meant that they had to require a lot of
所以这意味着他们不得不需要很多
compiling and maintaining of extra resources,
编制和维护额外资源，
and in fact, you had to have, uh,
事实上，你必须拥有，呃，
different resources for different languages.
不同语言的不同资源。
So the work kind of multiplied the more languages you had.
所以工作种类繁多，你拥有的语言越多。
An example of this, is you had to have,
这方面的一个例子是，你必须拥有，
uh, tables of equivalent phrases.
呃，等同短语的表格。
So for example if you're doing French and English translation, then, uh,
所以，例如，如果你正在做法语和英语翻译，那么，呃，
they would be collecting these phrases of, uh,
他们会收集这些短语，呃，
sorry these tables of phrases that they considered similar,
对不起这些他们认为相似的短语表，
and those were learned from the data.
这些都是从数据中学到的。
But this was a lot of information that had to be stored and maintained.
但这是必须存储和维护的大量信息。
So overall, this was just a lot of human effort to maintain.
总的来说，这只是人类维护的一大部分。
Uh, and again, yes,
呃，又一次，是的，
you had to put more human effort in if you wanted to
如果你愿意的话，你必须付出更多的努力
learn an SMT system for a new language pair.
学习SMT系统以获得新的语言对。
Okay, are there any questions here about, uh, SMT?
好的，这里有什么问题，呃，SMT？
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
Uh, so moving on, that's SMT.
呃，继续前进，这就是SMT。
[NOISE] Now, we're gonna move on to,
[NOISE]现在，我们要继续前进，
uh, section two of this lecture.
呃，这个讲座的第二部分。
So I want to take you back to the year 2014,
所以我想带你回到2014年，
for a dramatic re-enactment of what happened in
对于发生的事情进行了戏剧性的重演
the world of machine translation research.
机器翻译研究的世界。
So in 2014, something very dramatic happened and
所以在2014年，发生了非常戏剧性的事情
that thing that happened is called neural machine translation,
发生的那件事叫做神经机器翻译，
and [LAUGHTER] I think it looks a little
和[笑声]我觉得它看起来有点儿
bit like this [NOISE] if I'm not being too dramatic.
如果我不太戏剧化，就像这样[NOISE]
So what is neural machine translation?
那么什么是神经机器翻译？
The idea is that NMT is a way to do
这个想法是NMT是一种方法
machine translation but using just a single neural network.
机器翻译，但只使用一个神经网络。
[NOISE] And the neural network architecture that they use
[NOISE]和他们使用的神经网络架构
is called Sequence-to-Sequence or sometimes just called seq2seq,
称为序​​列到序列或有时称为seq2seq，
uh, and involves two RNNs.
呃，涉及两个RNN。
So, uh, it's called sequence-to-sequence,
所以，呃，它被称为序列到序列，
because you're mapping one sequence to the other.
因为你将一个序列映射到另一个序列。
The source sentence [NOISE] to the target sentence and you need two RNNs,
目标句子的源句[NOISE]，你需要两个RNN，
basically to handle those two different sentences.
基本上处理那两个不同的句子。
All right, lets look at the diagram to see what sequences-to-sequence is in detail.
好吧，让我们看一下图表，看看详细的序列到序列。
So we start off with our source sentence,
所以我们从源语句开始，
and we're gonna use our example from before
我们将使用之前的例子
il a m'entarte, which means, he hit me with a pie.
il a m'entarte，这意味着，他用馅饼打我。
So we, uh, feed this into our encoder RNN,
所以我们，呃，把它喂给我们的编码器RNN，
and this is as you've seen before,
这就像你以前见过的那样，
I've drawn a uni-directional RNN,
我画了一个单向的RNN，
but this could be bi-directional.
但这可能是双向的。
It also could be multi-layer.
它也可以是多层的。
It could be vanilla, or it could be LSTM, and so on.
它可能是香草，也可能是LSTM，依此类推。
Uh, another thing to note is that [NOISE] we are
呃，另外需要注意的是我们是[NOISE]
passing word embeddings into this encoder RNN,
将字嵌入传递给此编码器RNN，
but I'm just not explicitly depicting that step.
但我只是没有明确地描述那一步。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So the idea of the encoder RNN is that it's going to
所以编码器RNN的想法就是这样
produce some kind of encoding of this source sentence.
产生这种源句的某种编码。
So for now, let's assume that the encoding of the source sentence is going to be,
那么现在，让我们假设源句的编码将是，
uh, the final hidden state of this encoder RNN.
呃，这个编码器RNN的最终隐藏状态。
So what happens next is we pass this encoding of the source sentence.
那么接下来发生的是我们传递源句的这种编码。
We pass it over to the decoder RNN,
我们把它传递给解码器RNN，
which is going to translate into English.
这将翻译成英文。
So the decoder RNN is a language model.
因此解码器RNN是语言模型。
In particular, it's a conditional language model,
特别是，它是一种条件语言模型，
like we talked about last time.
就像我们上次谈到的那样。
So it's conditional because it's going to produce the target sentence,
所以它是有条件的，因为它会产生目标句子，
but conditioned on this encoding,
但是以这种编码为条件，
and the encoding is that vector that has the orange box around it.
编码是那个周围有橙色框的矢量。
So how does this work? Uh, we start off by feeding, uh,
那么这是如何工作的呢？呃，我们从喂食开始，呃，
the start token into the decoder, and then, uh,
启动令牌进入解码器，然后，呃，
we can get the first state of the decoder,
我们可以得到解码器的第一个状态，
because we're using, uh,
因为我们正在使用，呃，
the encoding of the source sentence as the initial hidden state for the decoder.
源句的编码作为解码器的初始隐藏状态。
So then we get our first output from the decoder,
那么我们从解码器得到第一个输出，
which is a probability distribution of what word might come next,
这是接下来可能出现的单词的概率分布，
and let's suppose that we take the argmax over that,
让我们假设我们把argmax放在那个，
and then that gets us the word, uh, he.
然后那就让我们知道了，呃，他。
Which is in this case is correct,
在这种情况下是正确的，
because that's probably the word you should start with.
因为这可能就是你应该开始的那个词。
Okay, so then we just take the word,
好的，那么我们接受这个词，
he and then we feed it back into the decoder on the next step,
他然后我们在下一步将它反馈到解码器中，
and then we do the same thing again.
然后我们再做同样的事情。
We take argmax and we get a new word and we get he hit.
我们采取argmax，我们得到一个新词，我们得到他的命中。
So the idea here is you can co- uh, continue doing this operation and in that way,
所以这里的想法是你可以继续这样做，并以这种方式，
you're going to generate, uh,
你要生成，呃，
your target sentence, uh,
你的目标句子，呃，
which will be something like he hit me with a pie,
这就像他用馅饼打我一样，
and you stop once your decoder produces the end token.
并且一旦解码器产生结束令牌就停止。
So an important thing to note here,
所以在这里要注意一件重要的事情，
is that this picture is showing you what happens at test time.
是这张照片告诉你在测试时发生了什么。
This shows you how to generate text.
这将向您展示如何生成文本。
Uh, this isn't what happens during training.
呃，这不是训练期间发生的事情。
I'll show you what happens [NOISE] during training later.
我会告诉你在训练过程中会发生什么[NOISE]。
Uh, but this thing with the,
呃，但这件事，
the pink dotted arrows where you feed the word back in.
粉红色虚线箭头，你把这个词喂回来。
This is what you do to generate text at test time.
这是您在测试时生成文本的方法。
Any questions on this? Uh, oh,
对此有任何疑问？呃，哦，
another thing I should note is that you need two separate sets of word embeddings, right?
我应该注意的另一件事是你需要两套独立的字嵌入，对吧？
You need word embeddings for French words, and you need English word embeddings,
你需要为法语单词嵌入单词，你需要英文单词嵌入，
so that's kind of two separate sets,
所以这是两个独立的集合，
two separate vocabularies. Um, yeah.
两个单独的词汇表。嗯，是的
Okay. So as a side note, uh,
好的。所以作为旁注，呃，
this architecture called sequence-to-sequence is actually pretty versatile.
这种称为序列到序列的架构实际上非常通用。
It's not just a machine translation architecture.
它不仅仅是一个机器翻译架构。
Uh, you can, uh, uh,
呃，你可以，呃，呃，
phrase quite a few NLP tasks as sequence-to-sequence tasks.
将相当多的NLP任务称为序列到序列任务。
Uh, so for example a summarization is
呃，举个例子就是总结
a sequence-to-sequence task because in goes your long text and out comes your short text.
一个序列到序列的任务，因为在你的长文本和你的短文本。
Uh, dialogue can [NOISE] be seq2seq because in
呃，对话可以[NOISE]是seq2seq，因为在
goes the previous utterance and out comes your next utterance, uh,
是先前的话语，然后是你的下一个话语，呃，
parsing can even be thought of as a sequence-to-sequence task,
解析甚至可以被认为是一个序列到序列的任务，
because you could say in goes the input text and
因为你可以说输入文本和
the output parse is going to be expressed as a sequence.
输出解析将表示为序列。
This might not be the best way to do parsing but it is a way you can try.
这可能不是解析的最佳方式，但这是一种可以尝试的方法。
Lastly, you could even do something like code generation.
最后，您甚至可以执行代码生成等操作。
So suppose you want to build a system that takes some kind of,
所以假设你想构建一个需要某种系统的系统，
uh, natural language input,
呃，自然语言输入，
such as sum up the numbers from 1-10 and then it outputs,
比如将1-10中的数字相加然后输出，
let's say some Python code that says,
让我们说一些Python代码说，
sum open brackets range 10 or something like that.
和开放括号范围10或类似的东西。
Uh, so if you wanted to train,
呃，如果你想训练，
um, an assistant to do this.
嗯，这是一个助手。
You could in a way view that as a translation task,
您可以在某种程度上将其视为翻译任务，
where you're translating from English to Python.
你在哪里从英语翻译成Python。
It's a pretty challenging translation task.
这是一项非常具有挑战性的翻译任务。
It probably requires a lot more logic than just uh, you know,
它可能需要更多的逻辑，而不仅仅是呃，你知道，
French to English [NOISE] but you can try and people have tried.
法语到英语[NOISE]，但你可以尝试，人们已经尝试过。
There are research papers where people have used seq2seq to do this kind of task.
有研究论文，人们使用seq2seq来完成这类任务。
Okay. So to recap, uh,
好的。所以回顾一下，呃，
seq2seq is an example of a conditional language model.
seq2seq是条件语言模型的示例。
Uh, it's a language model because the decoder
呃，这是一种语言模型，因为解码器
is a language model that's predicting the next target words.
是一种预测下一个目标词的语言模型。
But it's a conditional language model because it's also conditioning on
但它是一种条件语言模型，因为它也适应
your source sentence which is represented by the encoding of the source sentence.
你的源句，由源句的编码表示。
So you could look,
所以你可以看，
you could view it like this.
你可以这样看。
NMT is directly calculating the probability
NMT直接计算概率
of the target sentence y given the source sentence x.
给定源句x的目标句子y。
So if you look at this, you see that this is just, uh,
所以如果你看看这个，你会发现这只是，呃，
breaking down the probability of the sequence y,
打破序列y的概率，
which we suppose is of length, uh,
我们认为是长度的，呃，
capital T. You can break it down into the being the probability of
资本T.你可以把它分解为概率
the first word of y given x and then the probability of the second word of y given,
y给出x的第一个单词，然后给出y的第二个单词的概率，
uh, the words that came before, and x, and so on.
呃，之前的话，和x，等等。
So in fact, you can see that each of the terms in this product on the right,
所以实际上，你可以看到右边的这个产品中的每个术语，
those are probabilities of the next target word
那些是下一个目标词的概率
given all the ones so far, and also the source sentence,
考虑到目前为止所有的，以及源句，
and that's exactly the conditional probability that your language model produces.
这正是语言模型产生的条件概率。
So the reason I'm highlighting this is because if you remember in SMT, uh,
所以我突出这个的原因是因为如果你记得SMT，呃，
we didn't directly learn the translation model p of y given x,
我们没有直接学习给定x的y的翻译模型p，
we broke it down into,
我们把它分解成了，
uh, uh, smaller components.
呃，呃，较小的组件。
Whereas here in NMT,
而在NMT，
we are directly learning this model.
我们正在直接学习这个模型。
And this is in some ways an advantage because it's simpler to do.
这在某些方面是一个优势因为它更简单。
You don't have to learn all of these different systems and optimize them separately.
您无需学习所有这些不同的系统并单独进行优化。
It's, uh, kind of, simpler and easier.
它，呃，更简单，更容易。
So, uh, this is,
所以，呃，这是，
this is the model that we're learning.
这是我们正在学习的模型。
Uh, the question is, how do we train this NMT system?
呃，问题是，我们如何训练这个NMT系统？
So hopefully, you should already have a good idea of how this would work,
所以希望你应该已经知道这将如何工作，
given that we've already seen how you would train a language model.
鉴于我们已经看到你将如何培养语言模型。
But here are the details just in case.
但这里有详细信息以防万一。
So you get your big, uh, parallel corpus.
所以你得到了你的大而平行的语料库。
Uh, and then, uh,
呃，然后，呃，
let's say you have your sentence pair from your parallel corpus.
假设您从平行语料库中得到了句子对。
Uh, so this is what happens during training.
呃，这就是训练期间发生的事情。
Uh, you feed your source sentence into the encoder RNN, uh,
呃，你把你的源句写入编码器RNN，呃，
and then you feed your target sentence into the decoder RNN,
然后你将你的目标句子送入解码器RNN，
and you're going to pass over that
你会过去的
final hidden state to be the initial hidden state of the decoder.
最终隐藏状态是解码器的初始隐藏状态。
And then, uh, for every step of the decoder RNN,
然后，呃，对于解码器RNN的每一步，
you're going to produce the, uh,
你要生产，呃，
probability distribution of what comes next,
接下来的概率分布，
which is the, the y hats.
是帽子，是帽子。
And then from those,
然后从那些，
you can compute your loss.
你可以计算你的损失。
And the loss is just the same as we saw for,
损失与我们看到的一样，
u h, unconditional language models.
呃，无条件的语言模型。
It's, uh, the cross entropy or you could also
这是，呃，交叉熵，或者你也可以
say negative log-likelihood of the true next word.
说真实的下一个单词的负对数似然。
So for example, on those selected ones, uh,
那么，例如，那些选定的，呃，
the loss is the negative log probability of the correct next word.
损失是正确的下一个单词的负对数概率。
And then as before, we're going to average all of
然后和以前一样，我们将平均所有
these losses to get the total loss for the example.
这些损失可以得到总损失的例子。
Uh, so a thing you might notice people saying in,
呃，你可能会注意到有人在说，
for example, research papers is this phrase end-to-end.
例如，研究论文是端到端的这个短语。
And this is an example of learning a system end-to-end.
这是学习端到端系统的一个例子。
And what we mean by this is that the backpropagation is happening end-to-end, one end is,
我们的意思是反向传播是端到端发生的，一端是，
is losses, the loss functions,
是损失，损失功能，
and the other end I guess is kind of like the,
而另一端我觉得有点像，
the beginning of the encoder RNN.
编码器RNN的开头。
The point is that you, uh,
关键是你，呃，
backpropagation, uh, flows throughout the entire system,
反向传播，呃，流过整个系统，
and you learn the entire system with respect to this single, uh, loss. Yep?
并且你学习了整个系统，关于这个单一的，呃，损失。是的？
[inaudible]
[听不见]
The question is,
问题是，
if the decoder RNN outputs the end token too early,
如果解码器RNN过早输出结束令牌，
then how can you measure the loss on,
那你怎么测量损失，
uh, the words that came after that?
呃，之后的话呢？
So this is the difference between training time and test time,
所以这是培训时间和测试时间之间的差异，
which is pretty confusing.
这很令人困惑。
So, uh, during training,
那么，呃，在训练中，
we have this picture where you feed the token back in.
我们有这张图片，您可以将令牌送回来。
So in this scenario,
所以在这种情况下，
once you produce end,
一旦你产生了结束，
then you have to stop because you can't feed end in as the initial next step.
然后你必须停止，因为你不能作为最初的下一步结束。
But in training, you don't feed the thing that you produced into the next step.
但是在训练中，你不会将你制作的东西喂给下一步。
During training, you feed the target sentence from the corpus.
在训练期间，您从语料库中提取目标句子。
So like the gold target sentence into the model.
所以就像进入模型的黄金目标句子一样。
So no matter what the, uh,
无论如何，呃，
the decoder predicts on a step,
解码器预测一步，
you kind of, you don't use that for anything other than computing loss.
你有点，除了计算损失之外，你不要用它。
Any other questions? Yeah.
还有其他问题吗？是啊。
Is there a reason why you would, uh, backpropagation end-to-end instead of maybe
你有没有理由，呃，反向传播端到端而不是可能
training an encoder like [inaudible] model and then [inaudible] together?
像[听不清]模型一样训练编码器，然后一起[听不清]？
The question is, is there a reason why you would want to train end-to-end when,
问题是，你有什么理由想要在端到端训练的时候，
for example, you might want to train the encoder and the decoder separately?
例如，您可能想要单独训练编码器和解码器？
Uh, so I think, uh, people view training end-to-end as favorable
呃，我想，呃，人们认为端到端培训是有利的
because the idea is that you can optimize the system as a whole.
因为这个想法是你可以整体优化系统。
You might think that if you optimize the part separately,
您可能会认为如果您单独优化零件，
then when you put them together,
然后当你把它们放在一起时，
they will not be optimal together necessarily.
它们不一定是最佳的。
So if possible, directly optimizing the thing that you care abou-
所以如果可能的话，直接优化你关心的东西 -
about with respect to all of the parameters is more likely to succeed.
关于所有参数的概率更有可能成功。
However, there is a notion of pre-training.
但是，有一种预训练的概念。
And as you said, maybe you'd want to learn your, um,
正如你所说，也许你想学习你的，嗯，
decoder RNN as a kind of a language model,
解码器RNN作为一种语言模型，
an unconditional language model by itself.
一个无条件的语言模型本身。
And that's something that people do.
这就是人们所做的事情。
You might, uh, learn a very strong language model,
你可能，呃，学习一个非常强大的语言模型，
and then use that to initialize your decoder RNN,
然后用它来初始化你的解码器RNN，
and then fine-tune it on your task.
然后在你的任务上微调它。
That's a, a valid thing you might try to do.
这是一个，你可能会尝试做的有效事情。
Yep.
是的。
Are you always [inaudible]
你总是[音频不清晰]
The question is, is the length of
问题是，是长度
the source sentence and the length of the target sentence fixed?
源句和目标句的长度是固定的吗？
So for example, is the source sentence always length 4?
那么例如，源句总是长度为4？
Uh, no.
呃，不。
That's definitely not true because in your parallel corpus,
这绝对不是真的，因为在你的平行语料库中，
you're going to have sentences of all lengths.
你会得到各种长度的句子。
Uh, so this is more kind of an implementation or a practicality question.
呃，所以这更像是一种实现或实用性问题。
Uh, the idea is that this is what you mathematically want
呃，这个想法是这就是你在数学上想要的
to be computing during training for each example,
在每个例子的训练期间计算，
and you're going to have batches of examples.
而你将会有一批例子。
But the question is, how do you actually implement them in, uh, in practice?
但问题是，你如何在实践中实际实现它们？
So what you usually do just because it's easier to assume that your
所以你通常做的只是因为你更容易假设你的
batch is this kind of even-sized tensor where everything is the same length,
批量是这种均匀尺寸的张量，其中一切都是相同的长度，
is you pad any short sentences up to some predefined maximum length,
你是否填写任何预定义的最大长度的短句，
or maybe the length of the maximum example in your batch, uh,
或者你的批次中最大例子的长度，呃，
and then you make sure that you don't
然后你确保你没有
use any hidden states that came from the padding. Yep.
使用来自填充的任何隐藏状态。是的。
I believe two languages together [inaudible]
我相信两种语言[音频不清晰]
possible to have a system
可能有一个系统
[inaudible] that will be kind of universal with similar languages or something like that?
[音频不清晰]，类似的语言或其类似的东西会是什么样的？
Okay. So the question I think is,
好的。所以我认为的问题是，
uh, it seems like sometimes you wouldn't want to train things end-to-end,
呃，有时候你似乎不想端到端地训练东西，
and there are circumstances in which you might want to train things separately,
在某些情况下你可能想要分开训练，
and you mentioned, for example,
你提到过，例如，
having, uh, different languages mapped to each other.
有，呃，不同的语言相互映射。
So this is a totally valid point,
所以这是一个完全有效的观点，
and in fact, uh, so far we've, kind of,
事实上，呃，到目前为止，我们有点，
assumed that you want to learn language A to language B as a pair, right?
假设你想学习语言A作为一对语言B，对吗？
And that's different to language A to language C or even language B to language A.
这与语言A到语言C甚至语言B到语言A的不同。
And, um, that does mean you have kind of n-squared many systems in the number of,
并且，嗯，这确实意味着你有许多n平方的系统，
uh, languages you're considering.
呃，你正在考虑的语言。
So, yeah, that's actually a valid idea,
所以，是的，这实际上是一个有效的想法，
and this is something that people have researched.
这是人们研究过的东西。
The idea that maybe you could have a, kind of,
也许你可以有一种，一种，
mix and match with your encoders and decoders.
与您的编码器和解码器混合搭配。
And you could try to, uh, train a kind of general purpose,
你可以尝试，呃，培养一种通用目的，
let's say English decoder and then match it up with your different encoders.
让我们说英语解码器，然后将其与您的不同编码器匹配。
Uh, but this is, I think fairly complex to train to,
呃，但是，我认为训练相当复杂，
to make sure that they all work together.
确保他们一起工作。
But that, that is certainly something that people have done.
但那，这肯定是人们所做的事情。
Let me just check on the time.
我来看看时间。
Okay. Let's take one more question. Yep.
好的。我们再问一个问题。是的。
So does the word embedding also come from the same corpus that we are training on?
嵌入这个词也来自我们正在训练的同一语料库吗？
The question is, does the word embedding
问题是，嵌入这个词了吗？
also come from the corpus that you're training on?
也来自你正在训练的语料库？
So I think there's a few options just as we saw with language models; you could download,
所以我认为有一些选项正如我们在语言模型中看到的那样;你可以下载，
uh, pretrained word vectors like Word2Vec or GloVe,
呃，预训练的单词向量，如Word2Vec或GloVe，
and you could use those.
你可以用那些。
And then you can either, kind of, freeze them or you could
然后你可以，或者某种程度，冻结他们或你可以
fine-tune them as part of the end-to-end training,
将它们作为端到端培训的一部分进行微调，
or you could just initialize your word vectors as,
或者您可以将单词向量初始化为，
uh, you know, close to zero random and then learn them from scratch.
呃，你知道，接近零随机，然后从头开始学习它们。
All right. Okay, moving on.
行。好的，继续前进。
Uh, so now we understand how you would train a neural machine translation system.
呃，现在我们了解你将如何训练神经机器翻译系统。
And we talked briefly about how you might,
我们简要谈到了你的意愿，
uh, do decoding or generation.
呃，做解码或生成。
So what I showed you before is something called, uh, greedy decoding,
所以我之前向你展示的东西叫做呃贪婪的解码，
which is this idea that on each step,
这个想法就是每一步，
you just choose the argmax,
你只需选择argmax，
the top one best word,
最好的一个词，
and then you feed that in on the next step.
然后在下一步中将其输入。
So this is called greedy decoding because you're just taking the best, uh,
所以这被称为贪婪解码，因为你只是采取最好的，呃，
the best option that you can see right now,
你现在能看到的最佳选择，
and then you really don't have a way to go back.
然后你真的没有办法回去。
So can anyone see a problem with this method? Maybe I've kind of given it away but, uh, yeah.
那么有人能看到这个方法的问题吗？也许我有点放弃了，但是，呃，是的。
[inaudible].
[听不见的。
You said too expensive.
你说太贵了。
Um, I guess I mean it is expensive in that you have to do
嗯，我想我的意思是你要做的事情很贵
a sequence and the sequence is usually worse than something you can do in parallel.
一个序列和序列通常比你可以并行做的更糟糕。
But I suppose, um, maybe what's wrong with the greediness?
但我想，嗯，也许贪婪可能有什么问题？
Can anyone suggest what's wrong with the greediness, yeah?
任何人都可以说贪婪有什么不对，是吗？
[inaudible] [NOISE] That's not
[听不清] [NOISE]那不是
necessarily gonna give you the argmax over the entire sentence.
必须要给你整个句子的argmax。
That's exactly right. That's, uh,
这是完全正确的。那是，呃，
kind of what, uh, what greediness means.
什么，呃，贪婪意味着什么。
So in practice, this might give you something like this.
所以在实践中，这可能会给你这样的东西。
Uh, we're trying to translate
呃，我们正在尝试翻译
our running example sentence and let's suppose on the first step we say,
我们运行的例句，让我们假设在第一步，我们说，
"He," and then we say,
“他，”然后我们说，
"He hit," and then we say,
“他打了，”然后我们说，
"He hit a," oh no, that wasn't right.
“他打了一个，”哦不，那不对。
That wasn't the best thing to choose but we kinda have no way to go back now, right.
这不是最好的选择，但我们现在无法回头，对吧。
We just have to continue and try to make the best of it after saying,
我们必须继续并尝试充分利用它，然后说，
"He hit a," which isn't gonna work out well.
“他打了一个，”这不会很好。
So that's the main problem with greedy decoding.
所以这是贪婪解码的主要问题。
There's kind of no way to backtrack, no way to go back.
有一种无法回溯的方式，无法回头。
So how can we fix this?
那我们怎么解决这个问题呢？
And this relates back to, uh,
这与呃相关
what I told you earlier about how we might use, uh,
我之前告诉你的关于我们如何使用的信息，呃，
a kind of searching algorithm to do decoding and SMT.
一种搜索算法，用于解码和SMT。
Uh, but first, you might,
呃，但首先，你可能，
uh, think exhaustive search is a good idea.
呃，想想详尽的搜索是个好主意。
Well, probably not because it's still a bad idea for the same reasons as before.
嗯，可能不是因为它仍然是一个坏主意，出于与以前相同的原因。
So if you did want to do exhaustive search,
所以，如果你确实想做详尽的搜索，
and search through the space of all possible French translations, uh,
并搜索所有可能的法语翻译空间，呃，
then you would be again,
然后你会再次，
trying to consider which Y maximizes,
试图考虑哪个Y最大化，
uh, this product of all of these individual probability distributions.
呃，所有这些个体概率分布的这个乘积。
So as before, if you try to do this,
和以前一样，如果你试着这样做，
uh, then on each step T of the decoder,
呃，然后在解码器的每个步骤T，
you're gonna be having to track V to the power of T possible partial translations,
你将不得不追踪V到T的可能部分翻译的力量，
uh, where V is your vocabulary size.
呃，V是你的词汇量。
So here when I say partial translation,
所以当我说部分翻译时，
I just mean, uh, a kinda,
我只是说，呃，有点儿，
you know, like, half of a sentence so far, or something like that.
你知道，到目前为止一半的句子，或类似的东西。
So, of course, this, uh,
那么，当然，这个，呃，
exponential in V complexity is just far too expensive.
V复杂度的指数过于昂贵。
So yes, we're gonna use some kind of search algorithm,
所以，是的，我们将使用某种搜索算法，
and in particular, we're gonna use a beam search decoding.
特别是，我们将使用波束搜索解码。
So the core idea of beam search decoding is that on each step of the decoder,
因此，光束搜索解码的核心思想是在解码器的每一步，
you're gonna be keeping track of the K most probable partial translations,
你要跟踪K最可能的部分翻译，
and we call partial translations hypotheses,
我们称之为部分翻译假设，
because we're kind of tracking multiple of them and we're not sure which one is best.
因为我们有点跟踪他们的多个，我们不确定哪一个是最好的。
So we're thinking about several.
所以我们考虑几个。
Here K is an integer and we call this the beam size,
这里K是一个整数，我们称之为光束大小，
and in practice for NMT this is usually maybe 5-10.
在NMT的实践中，这通常可能是5-10。
So you can think of, uh,
所以你可以想到，呃，
K kind of as how big is your search space at any one time.
K类似于你的搜索空间在任何时候都有多大。
So if you increase K, then you're going to be
所以，如果你增加K，那么你将会是
considering more different options on each step
考虑每个步骤的更多不同选项
and you might hope that this will mean that you get
你可能希望这意味着你得到了
the best quality solution in the end though of course it'll be more expensive.
最终质量最好的解决方案，当然它会更贵。
So I said that we want to keep track of
所以我说我们要跟踪
the K most probable partial translations, that is, hypotheses.
K最可能的部分翻译，即假设。
So this means that we need some kind of notion of, you know,
所以这意味着我们需要某种概念，你知道，
how probable is this hypothesis or what's its score.
这个假设有多大可能或者得分是多少。
So the score of a hypothesis and, uh,
那么假设的得分，呃，
we're representing that as Y_1 up to Y_T,
我们将Y_1表示为Y_T，
um, is just its log probability.
嗯，只是它的对数概率。
So, uh, the log probability of this partial translation, uh,
那么，呃，这部分翻译的对数概率，呃，
according to the language model can be broken down as we saw before into the sum of
根据语言模型可以分解为我们之前看到的总和
the individual log probabilities of the words given everything that came before.
给出之前所有内容的单词的单独日志概率。
So it's, if it's not obvious, uh,
所以，如果它不明显，呃，
these scores are all negative because we're taking log of,
这些分数都是负数，因为我们正在记录，
uh, of a number between 0 and 1.
呃，0到1之间的数字。
Uh, and a higher score is better.
呃，分数越高越好。
Yes, because you want a higher probability of,
是的，因为你想要更高的概率，
uh, of the hypothesis according to the language model.
呃，根据语言模型的假设。
So the idea is that we're gonna use this score, uh,
所以这个想法是我们要用这个分数，呃，
and the search algorithm to search for
以及搜索的搜索算法
high-scoring hypotheses and we're gonna track the top K on each step.
高分的假设，我们将在每一步追踪前K。
So I'm gonna show you a detailed example in a moment,
所以我马上就会给你一个详细的例子，
but the important thing is to know
但重要的是要知道
that beam search is not guaranteed to find an optimal solution.
光束搜索无法保证找到最佳解决方案。
Uh, exhaustive search, the one where you enumerate,
呃，详尽的搜索，你列举的那个，
enumerate all V to the T possible translations, that is guaranteed to find
枚举所有V到T的可能翻译，保证找到
the optimal solution but it is just completely infeasible because it's so expensive.
最佳解决方案，但它是完全不可行的，因为它是如此昂贵。
So beam search is not guaranteed to find the optimal solution,
所以光束搜索不能保证找到最佳解决方案，
but it is much more efficient than exhaustive search of course.
但它当然比穷举搜索更有效率。
Okay. So, um, here's an example of beam search decoding in action.
好的。那么，嗯，这是一个实际的光束搜索解码的例子。
Uh, so let's suppose the beam size equals K, uh,
呃，我们假设光束大小等于K，呃，
is 2 and then as a reminder, we have, uh,
是2然后作为提醒，我们有，呃，
this is the score that you apply to a partial, uh,
这是你应用于部分的分数，呃，
hypothesis, uh, a partial translation,
假设，呃，部分翻译，
which is a hypothesis.
这是一个假设。
So we start off with our starting token,
所以我们从我们的起始令牌开始，
and the idea is that we're going to compute
我们的想法是我们要计算
the probability distribution of what word might come next.
接下来可能会出现什么词的概率分布。
So having computed that probability distribution using our seq2seq model,
因此，使用我们的seq2seq模型计算了该概率分布，
then we just take the top K, that is top two possible options.
然后我们只选择前K，这是两个可能的选择。
So let's suppose that the top two are the words "He" and "I".
所以我们假设前两位是“他”和“我”。
So the idea is that we can compute the score of these two hypotheses,
所以我们的想法是我们可以计算出这两个假设的得分，
uh, by using the formula above.
呃，使用上面的公式。
It's just the log probability of this word given the context so far.
到目前为止，这只是给出上下文的这个词的对数概率。
So here, let's say that "He" has a score of -0,7 and "I" has a score of -0,9.
所以在这里，让我们说“他”得分为-0,7，“我”得分为-0,9。
So this means that he is currently the best one.
所以这意味着他目前是最好的一个。
Okay. So what we do is, uh,
好的。所以我们做的是，呃，
we have our two, uh, K hypotheses,
我们有两个，呃，K假设，
and then for each of those,
然后对于每一个，
we find the top K words that could come next.
我们找到了接下来可能出现的前K个词。
And we calculate their scores.
我们计算他们的分数。
So this means that for both "He" and "I" we find the top two words that could come next.
所以这意味着对于“他”和“我”，我们找到了接下来可能出现的前两个词。
And for each of these four possibilities, uh,
对于这四种可能性中的每一种，呃，
the score of the hypothesis is equal to, uh,
假设的得分等于，呃，
the log probability of this new word given the context so far plus
给出上下文的这个新单词的对数概率加上
the score so far because you can accumulate the sum of low probabilities.
到目前为止的分数，因为你可以积累低概率的总和。
You don't have to compute it from scratch each time.
您不必每次都从头开始计算它。
So here you can see that we have these four possibilities and that
所以在这里你可以看到我们有这四种可能性
the top two scores are -1,6 and -1,7.
前两个得分分别为-1,6和-1,7。
So this means that hit and was are the two best ones.
所以这意味着击中并且是最好的两个。
So the idea is that of these K squared equals 4 hypotheses,
所以这个想法是这些K平方等于4个假设，
we're just gonna keep the K equals 2 top ones.
我们要保持K等于2个顶级。
And then we just keep doing the same thing.
然后我们继续做同样的事情。
For these two, we expand to get the two next ones.
对于这两个，我们扩展以获得下两个。
And then of those we compute the scores,
然后我们计算得分，
and then we keep the two best ones and discard the others and then of those, we expand.
然后我们保留两个最好的并丢弃其他的，然后我们扩展。
So we keep doing this again and again,
所以我们一次又一次地这样做，
expanding and then just keeping the top K and expanding like this until,
扩展，然后保持顶部K并像这样扩展，直到，
uh, you get some kinda, uh, finished translation.
呃，你得到一些，呃，完成翻译。
I'm going to tell you more in a moment about what exactly the stopping criterion is.
我稍后会告诉你更多关于停止标准的内容。
But let's suppose that we stop here.
但我们假设我们就此止步。
Uh, looking at the four hypotheses that we have on the far right,
呃，看看我们在最右边的四个假设，
the one with the top score is, uh,
得分最高的是，呃，
the top pie one with -4,3.
顶部馅饼一个-4,3。
So let's suppose that we are gonna stop now when we
所以我们假设我们现在要停止了
decide that this is the top hypothesis,
认为这是最重要的假设，
then all we need to do is just backtrack
那么我们所需要做的只是回溯
through this tree in order to find the full translation,
通过这棵树，以找到完整的翻译，
which is "He hit me with the pie."
这是“他用馅饼打我。”
All right. So, um, let me tell you more detail about how exactly we decide when to stop.
行。所以，嗯，让我告诉你更多关于我们如何决定何时停止的细节。
So if you remember in greedy decoding,
所以，如果你记得在贪婪的解码，
usually we just keep decoding until the model produces the END token.
通常我们只是继续解码，直到模型产生END令牌。
So for example, this means that your model is actually producing the sequence, uh,
因此，例如，这意味着您的模型实际上正在生成序列，呃，
I guess it doesn't produce START,
我猜它不会产生START，
you give it START but then it produces the sequence "He hit me with a pie" END.
你给它START，然后它产生序列“他用馅饼打我”END。
So the problem in beam search decoding is
所以光束搜索解码的问题是
that you're considering all these different hypotheses,
你正在考虑所有这些不同的假设，
K different hypotheses at once and the thing is
K不同的假设一下子就是了
those hypotheses might produce END tokens at different times.
这些假设可能会在不同时间产生END令牌。
So there's no one obvious place to stop.
所以没有一个明显的地方可以阻止。
So what we do in practice,
那么我们在实践中做了什么，
is when a hypothesis produces the END token,
当假设产生END令牌时，
then we regard this hypothesis as complete and we kind of place it aside.
那么我们认为这个假设是完整的，我们把它放在一边。
We have a collection of completed hypothesis.
我们收集了完整的假设。
So we kind of take it out of beam search,
所以我们把它从光束搜索中拿出来，
we no longer keep exploring it because it's finished,
我们不再继续探索它，因为它已经完成，
uh, and we, yeah, place it aside.
呃，我们，是的，把它放在一边。
And you continue exploring other hypotheses with beam search.
然后你继续探索光束搜索的其他假设。
So the remaining question is when do you stop doing beam search?
所以剩下的问题是你什么时候停止进行光束搜索？
When do you stop iterating through this algorithm?
你什么时候停止迭代这个算法？
So there's, uh, uh, multiple possible stopping criterion
所以，呃，呃，多个可能的停止标准
but two common ones are you might say, uh,
但你可能会说两个常见的，呃，
we're gonna stop doing beam search once we reach time step T,
一旦我们到达时间步T，我们将停止进行光束搜索，
where T is some, uh,
T是某些，呃，
predefined threshold that you choose.
您选择的预定义阈值。
So you might say, uh,
所以你可能会说，呃，
we're gonna stop beam search after 30 steps because we don't want
因为我们不想要，我们将在30步后停止光束搜索
any output sentences that are longer than 30 words for example,
例如，超过30个单词的任何输出句子，
or you might say, "Uh,
或者你可能会说，“呃，
we're gonna stop doing beam search once we've collected at least N completed hypotheses."
一旦我们收集了至少N个已完成的假设，我们就会停止进行光束搜索。“
So you might say, "Uh, I want
所以你可能会说，“呃，我想要
at least 10 complete translations before I stop doing beam search."
在我停止进行光束搜索之前至少有10个完整的翻译。“
Okay. So what's the final thing you have to do?
好的。那你最后要做的是什么？
Uh, we finished doing beam search, um,
呃，我们完成了光束搜索，嗯，
we have this collection of completed hypotheses.
我们有这个完整假设的集合。
Uh, we want to choose the top one.
呃，我们想选择最好的一个。
Uh, the one that we're going to use is our translation.
呃，我们将要使用的是我们的翻译。
So, uh, how do we select the top one that has the highest score?
那么，呃，我们如何选择得分最高的顶级？
Uh, you might think this is simple given that all of
呃，你可能会觉得这很简单
these hypotheses already have scores attached.
这些假设已经附加了分数。
But if we just look at this, uh,
但是，如果我们只看这个，呃，
formula again, uh, for what the score is of each hypothesis.
公式，呃，每个假设得分。
Uh, can anyone see a problem with this?
呃，有人能看到这个问题吗？
If we have our sets of hypotheses,
如果我们有一套假设，
and then we're choosing the top one
然后我们选择了最顶一个
based on the one that has the best score, can anyone see a problem?
基于得分最高的人，任何人都可以看到问题吗？
Yeah. [NOISE] So the answer was you're gonna end up choosing the shortest one.
是啊。 [NOISE]所以答案是你最终会选择最短的一个。
The problem here is that longer hypotheses have lower scores in
这里的问题是较长的假设得分较低
general because you're multiplying more probabilities so you're getting a smaller,
一般是因为你增加了更多的概率，所以你变小了，
a smaller overall value or I guess if we're adding
总体价值较小，或者我猜是否正在增加
low probabilities we're gonna get more negative values.
低概率我们会得到更多负面价值。
So it's not quite that you will definitely choose
所以你肯定不会选择它
the shortest hypothesis because if you could overall have,
最短的假设，因为如果你可以整体拥有，
uh, a lower score but there's definitely going to be a bias towards shorter translations,
呃，分数较低，但肯定会偏向较短的翻译，
uh, because they'll in general have lower scores.
呃，因为他们一般都会得分较低。
So the way you can fix this is pretty simple,
所以你可以解决这个问题很简单，
you just normalize by length.
你只是按长度标准化。
So instead of using the tools we have above, you're going to use, uh,
因此，不是使用我们上面使用的工具，而是使用，呃，
the score divided by [inaudible].
得分除以[听不清]。
And then you use this to select the top one.
然后你用它来选择最上面的一个。
Any questions on this? [NOISE].
对此有任何疑问？ [噪声]。
Yeah.
是啊。
Can we train with the END token so that it is possible to [inaudible]
我们可以使用END令牌进行训练，以便[听不清]
I didn't quite hear that, can you train with the END token?
我听不到，你能用END令牌训练吗？
Yeah, like we had an END token.
是的，就像我们有一个END令牌。
Yes. So you train with the END token, if that's your question.
是。所以你用END令牌训练，如果这是你的问题。
Um, because the whole point is you're relying on your language model,
嗯，因为重点在于你是依靠你的语言模型，
your decoder to produce the END token in order to know when to stop.
你的解码器产生END令牌，以便知道何时停止。
So you need to train it to produce the END token by giving it examples of
因此，您需要通过提供示例来训练它以生成END令牌
training sentences with END tokens. Yeah.
用END标记训练句子。是啊。
Why don't we use this score being changed [inaudible]
为什么我们不改变这个分数[音频不清晰]
Great question. The question is,
好问题。问题是，
why don't we use this normalized score,
为什么我们不使用这个标准化分数，
the one at the bottom of the screen during beam search in the first place?
首先在光束搜索期间屏幕底部的那个？
So the reason why that's not necessary,
所以没有必要，
you could, but it's not necessary,
你可以，但没有必要，
is because during beam search,
是因为在光束搜索期间，
we only ever compare the scores of hypotheses that have the same length, right?
我们只比较具有相同长度的假设得分，对吧？
So in each of these steps, the way we look at,
所以在每个步骤中，我们看待的方式，
let's say the top k squared and we want to choose which ones are the top k,
让我们说前k平方，我们想选择哪些是前k，
we're comparing the scores of four different hypotheses that are of length,
我们比较四种不同长度的假设的得分，
one, two, three, four, five.
一二三四五。
So, um, it's true that these scores are getting lower and lower,
所以，嗯，这些得分越来越低，
but in the same way because they're all length five right now.
但是以同样的方式，因为他们现在都是五岁。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So we now understand how you would train an NMT system and how would you- you
所以我们现在了解你将如何训练NMT系统，你会怎样
would use your trained NMT system to generate your translations using,
将使用您训练有素的NMT系统生成您的翻译，使用，
let's say, beam search.
让我们说，光束搜索。
So let's all take a step back and think about,
让我们都退后一步思考，
what are the overall advantages of NMT in comparison to SMT?
与SMT相比，NMT的整体优势是什么？
Uh, so the first advantage is just better performance.
呃，所以第一个优势就是更好的表现。
Uh, NMT systems tend to give better output than SMT systems in several ways.
呃，NMT系统往往在几个方面提供比SMT系统更好的输出。
One is that the output often tends to be more fluent.
一个是输出往往更流畅。
Uh, this is probably because NMT, uh,
呃，这可能是因为NMT，呃，
this is probably because RNNs are particularly good at
这可能是因为RNN特别擅长
learning language models as you learned last week.
学习上周学到的语言模型。
Uh, another way that they're better is they often use,
呃，他们经常使用的另一种方式是更好的，
uh, the context better, that is,
呃，环境更好，也就是说，
uh, they're better at conditioning on
呃，他们更善于调理
the source sentence and using that to change the output.
源句和使用它来改变输出。
Another way they're better is they often, uh,
他们更好的另一种方式是他们经常，呃，
are more able to generalize what they learn about phrases and how to translate them.
更能够概括他们对短语的学习以及如何翻译它们。
So for example, if it sees an example of how to translate a certain
例如，如果它看到了如何翻译某个特定的例子
source phrase and then later it sees a slightly different version of that source phrase,
源短语，然后它看到该源短语的略有不同的版本，
it's, uh, more able to generalize what
它，呃，更能够概括什么
it learned about the first phrase than SMT systems will.
它了解了第一个短语而不是SMT系统。
Another big advantage of NMT systems compared to SMT that we talked about
与我们谈到的SMT相比，NMT系统的另一大优势
before is that it's a single neural network that can be optimized end-to-end.
之前是它是一个可以端到端优化的单一神经网络。
And the- the advantage here I suppose is primarily simplicity and convenience.
而且 - 我认为这里的优势主要是简单和方便。
So there's no subcomponents that need to be individually optimized.
因此，没有需要单独优化的子组件。
Another big advantage is that it requires much less human engineering efforts.
另一个很大的优势是它需要更少的人力工程努力。
When I told you earlier about all the different things that
当我早些时候告诉你所有不同的事情时
people had to do to build, uh, big,
人们不得不做，呃，大，
uh, powerful SMT systems, uh,
呃，强大的SMT系统，呃，
there's relatively less engineering effort for NMT.
NMT的工程工作量相对较少。
And NMT is certainly not easy,
NMT肯定不容易，
but it's- is less complicated than SMT.
但它 - 比SMT复杂。
In particular, there's no feature engineering.
特别是，没有特征工程。
You don't have to define what features of,
你不必定义什么功能，
uh, linguistic phenomena that you want to capture.
呃，你想要捕捉的语言现象。
You can mostly just view it as a sequence of words although,
您可以将其视为一系列单词，但是，
uh, there are different views on that.
呃，对此有不同的看法。
Uh, lastly, a great thing about NMT is that you can
呃，最后，关于NMT的一件好事就是你可以
use pretty much the same method for all language pairs.
对所有语言对使用几乎相同的方法。
So if you've, uh, you know,
所以，如果你，呃，你知道，
built your French-to-English translation system
建立了您的法语 - 英语翻译系统
and now you want to build a Spanish-to-English one, [NOISE] uh,
现在你想建立一个西班牙语到英语的，[NOISE]呃，
you can probably use basically the same architecture and the same method
你可以使用基本相同的架构和相同的方法
as long as you can go find a big enough parallel corpus of Spanish-to-English.
只要你能找到一个足够大的西班牙语到英语的平行语料库。
All right. So what are the disadvantages of NMT, uh, remaining?
行。那么NMT的缺点是什么，呃，还剩下什么？
So compared to SMT,
所以与SMT相比，
there are some disadvantages.
有一些缺点。
One is that NMT is less interpretable.
一个是NMT不太可解释。
Uh, what I mean by this is you
呃，我的意思是你
feed in your source sentence into the neural network and then it feeds
将源语句中的内容输入神经网络，然后输入
out some target sentence and you didn't
出一些目标句而你却没有
really have any way to figure out why that happened, right?
真的有办法弄清楚为什么会这样，对吧？
So in particular, if the target sentence con- contains some kind of error,
所以特别是，如果目标句子包含某种错误，
um, you can't really look at the neurons and understand what happened.
嗯，你无法真正看到神经元并了解发生了什么。
It's pretty hard to attribute errors.
归因于错误很难。
So this means that, uh,
所以这意味着，呃，
NMT systems are pretty hard to debug.
NMT系统很难调试。
So by comparison, SMT systems were more
相比之下，SMT系统更多
interpretable in that you had all of
可解释的是你拥有所有的
these different sub-components that were doing different jobs.
这些不同的子组件正在做不同的工作。
And, uh, you were more able to look at those.
而且，呃，你更能看到那些。
They weren't, you know, neurons often would be, uh,
他们不是，你知道，神经元经常是，呃，
you know, probabilities of certain words given other words and so on.
你知道，给定其他单词的某些单词的概率等等。
And, you know, that's by no means easy to
而且，你知道，这绝不容易
interpret but it was at least more interpretable than NMT.
解释但它至少比NMT更容易理解。
Uh, another disadvantage is NMT is pretty difficult to control.
呃，另一个缺点是NMT很难控制。
So, uh, for example,
所以，呃，例如，
if your NMT system is,
如果您的NMT系统是，
uh, doing a particular error,
呃，做一个特别的错误，
it's not very easy for you, the, uh,
这对你来说不是很容易，呃，
programmer to specify some kind of
程序员指定某种
rule or guideline that you want the NMT system to follow.
您希望NMT系统遵循的规则或准则。
So for example, if you want to say,
所以，例如，如果你想说，
I want to always translate this word in this way.
我想一直用这种方式翻译这个词。
Um, when- when this other thing is present,
嗯，当这个其他的东西存在的时候，
like that's not particularly easy to, uh,
那样的不是特别容易，呃，
to impose as a rule on the NMT system, uh,
通常对NMT系统强加，呃，
because you can't, uh,
因为你不能，呃，
easily control what it's doing on a step-by-step basis.
轻松控制它一步一步做的事情。
So sometimes you have some kind of, uh,
所以有时你会有某种，呃，
post-processing rules you might try to do,
你可能会尝试做的后处理规则，
but overall you can't.
但总的来说你做不到。
It- it's- it's harder than you'd expect to try to, um,
它 - 它比你期望的更难，嗯，
impose a fairly simple form.
强加一个相当简单的形式。
[NOISE] So this means it has some kind of safety concerns in fact.
[NOISE]因此，这意味着它实际上存在某种安全问题。
Because, uh, let's say, you know,
因为，呃，让我们说，你知道，
you don't want your NMT system to say bad things, right?
你不希望你的NMT系统说坏话，对吧？
It's- it's pretty hard to actually put, um,
这真的很难，嗯，
these, uh, controls in
这些，呃，控制在
place to stop it from saying these things that you don't want it to say.
阻止它说出你不想说的这些东西的地方。
I mean, on the level of maybe just never saying particular bad words,
我的意思是，在可能只是从不说特别坏话的水平上，
then sure you can remove them from the vocabulary.
然后确定你可以从词汇表中删除它们。
But overall they're pretty hard to control,
但总的来说，它们很难控制，
and we're actually gonna see some examples of NMT systems being,
我们实际上会看到一些NMT系统的例子，
you know, doing things that their
你知道，做他们的事
uh, designers certainly didn't intend.
呃，设计师肯定不打算。
Okay. So, uh, how do we evaluate MT?
好的。所以，呃，我们如何评估MT？
Uh, every good NLP task needs to have
呃，每个好的NLP任务都需要
an automatic metric so that we can, uh, measure our progress.
一个自动指标，以便我们可以，呃，衡量我们的进步。
So the, uh, most commonly used evaluation metric for MT is
因此，对于MT来说，最常用的评估指标是
called BLEU and that stands for Bilingual Evaluation Understudy.
称为BLEU，代表双语评估Understudy。
So the main idea is that BLEU is gonna
所以主要的想法是BLEU会
compare the translation that's produced by your machine translation system.
比较机器翻译系统产生的翻译。
It's gonna compare that to
它会与之相比较
one or maybe several human written translations of the same sentence.
同一句话的一个或几个人类书面翻译。
And then it's gonna compute a similarity score that's based on n-gram precision.
然后它将计算基于n-gram精度的相似性得分。
So when I say n-gram precision,
所以当我说n-gram精度时，
I mean you're gonna look at all the one, two, three,
我的意思是你会看到所有的一，二，三，
and four grams that appear in your, uh,
你身上出现的四克，呃，
machine written translation and your human written translation.
机器书面翻译和你的人工书面翻译。
And then n-gram precision is basically saying,
然后n-gram精度基本上说，
for all of the n-grams that appeared in the machine-written translation,
对于机器翻译中出现的所有n-gram，
how many of those appeared in, you know,
你知道，有多少人出现在
at least one of the human-written translations?
至少有一个人性化的翻译？
Another thing that you need to add to BLEU is a brevity penalty.
你需要添加到BLEU的另一件事是简洁惩罚。
Uh, so you're saying that you get a lower BLEU score if
呃，所以你说如果你获得较低的BLEU分数
your system translation is significantly
你的系统翻译很重要
shorter than all of the human-written translations.
比所有人工书面翻译都要短。
And the reason why you need to add this is because
你需要添加它的原因是因为
n-gram precision alone doesn't [NOISE] really punish using, uh, fewer words.
单独的n-gram精度不会[NOISE]真正惩罚使用，呃，更少的单词。
So you might try to maximize n-gram precision by being very conservative and writing,
所以你可以尝试通过非常保守和写作来最大化n-gram精度，
uh, short sentences that only contain words that you're really sure about,
呃，只包含你真正相信的单词的短句，
and then you get a good precision score.
然后你获得了很好的精确分数。
But this doesn't make a good translation because you're probably missing a bunch of
但这并不是一个很好的翻译，因为你可能错过了很多
information that you needed to translate from the source sentence.
您需要从源句翻译的信息。
So that's why you need to add the brevity, uh, penalty.
这就是为什么你需要添加简洁，呃，惩罚。
So overall, um, BLEU is very useful because, uh,
总的来说，嗯，BLEU非常有用，因为，呃，
we need an automatic metric in order to, uh, measure progress,
我们需要一个自动指标来衡量进度，
you can't measure progress on human evaluation
你无法衡量人类评价的进展
alone because it takes too long [NOISE] to compute.
单独因为计算需要太长时间[NOISE]。
Um, but of course it's pretty and perfect.
嗯，但当然它非常完美。
So for example, you can think about how there
例如，你可以考虑一下
are many ways- many valid ways to translate a sentence.
有许多方法 - 翻译句子的许多有效方法。
At the very beginning of this lecture,
在本讲座的开头，
I asked how do we translate that sentence, uh,
我问我们如何翻译那句话，呃，
by Rousseau and there were at least a few different options that came up.
通过Rousseau，至少有几个不同的选择出现了。
Uh, so if there's many valid ways to translate a sentence,
呃，如果有很多有效的翻译方法，
how does BLEU recognize that?
BLEU如何认识到这一点？
BLEU is [NOISE] rewarding sentences that have a high n-gram overlap with,
BLEU是[NOISE]奖励与n-gram重叠的句子，
uh, one or some of the human-written translations.
呃，一个或一些人性化的翻译。
But, if, uh, you write one,
但是，如果，呃，你写一个，
if your model writes one valid translation and the humans wrote
如果你的模型写了一个有效的翻译并且人类写了
a different valid translation and they don't have high n-gram overlap,
一个不同的有效翻译，他们没有高n-gram重叠，
then BLEU is going to, uh, give you a low score.
那么BLEU会去，呃，给你一个低分。
So, um, you're going to learn about BLEU in detail in Assignment 4,
所以，嗯，你将在作业4中详细了解BLEU，
and in fact Assignment 4 has
事实上，作业4有
a full description- mathematical description of what the BLEU score is.
完整描述 -  BLEU分数的数学描述。
So I'm not gonna tell you about that now, uh, yes,
所以我现在不打算告诉你，呃，是的，
so you're gonna think about BLEU and the- the ways in which it's
所以你要考虑BLEU以及它的方式
imperfect but useful. Yeah.
不完美但有用。是啊。
So would one- one n-gram, be a one to one equivalency?
那么一个n-gram会是一对一的等价吗？
What?
什么？
Would a one n-gram be a one to one equivalency?
一个n-gram是一对一的等价吗？
The question is, would a one n-gram be a one-to-one equivalency?
问题是，一个n-gram是一对一的等价吗？
I'm not sure I understand the question. You're asking about alignment or something else?
我不确定我理解这个问题。你问的是对齐还是其他什么？
Uh, just trying to get an idea about how they're doing n-gram checks,
呃，只是想知道他们如何进行n-gram检查，
is it doing all n-gram permutations or is it doing like window size of one?
它是在做所有n-gram排列还是像窗口大小一样？
Well, I guess one- one n-gram it doesn't
嗯，我猜一个n-gram它没有
make a difference because you can't permute a one-gram.
有所作为，因为你无法置换一克。
Okay. So you're asking for examples,
好的。所以你要问的例子，
for four grams are they checking, uh,
四克是他们检查，呃，
whether this exact sequence of four paired or
是否这四个配对或精确序列
any permutation of it, its exact sequences?
它的任何排列，它的确切序列？
So by definition, n-grams are sequences where the order matters.
因此，根据定义，n-gram是顺序重要的序列。
Okay. All right.
好的。行。
So, uh, that's how you evaluate machine translation.
所以，呃，这就是你评估机器翻译的方式。
So now you can understand this metric of how we
所以现在你可以理解我们的这个指标
evaluate our progress on machine translation,
评估我们在机器翻译方面的进展
um, I can show you this graph and you might understand what it means.
嗯，我可以告诉你这个图表，你可能会理解这意味着什么。
So this is a, uh,
所以这是一个，呃，
bar plot which shows in a nutshell how NMT changed the machine translation,
条形图简洁地显示了NMT如何改变机器翻译，
uh, landscape in just a few years.
呃，几年后的景观。
So in this plot, we've got BLEU score is the Y-axis.
所以在这个情节中，我们得到的BLEU得分是Y轴。
Uh, and you have two different types of SMT
呃，你有两种不同类型的SMT
which is the red and the dark blue, uh, bar plots.
这是红色和深蓝色，呃，酒吧情节。
And what's happening is,
而且发生了什么，
uh, in 2015, uh,
呃，在2015年，呃，
Neural MT enters the scene for the first time and it isn't doi- doing as well as SMT,
神经MT第一次进入场景，它不像SMT那样做，
and then the next year it's suddenly outperforming SMT.
然后第二年它突然超越了SMT。
And here these are BLEU scores on some particular fixed dataset like,
这里是一些特定固定数据集的BLEU分数，如：
uh, a shared task that many people were,
呃，很多人都有共同的任务，
um, submitting systems for.
嗯，提交系统。
[NOISE] So the main thing to notice here is
[NOISE]所以这里要注意的主要是
that the progress that was being made by SMT systems was,
SMT系统正在取得的进展是，
you know, a fairly gentle increase in BLEU year-by-year.
你知道，BLEU逐年增加相当温和。
And then in just one year,
然后在短短一年内，
NMT arrives and is suddenly doing,
NMT到达并突然发生，
uh, much more rapid progress.
呃，进展更快。
So I think this justifies why the picture of the meteor maybe isn't too Jurassic here.
所以我认为这证明了为什么流星的图片在这里可能不是太侏罗纪。
So you could in fact call NMT the biggest success story of NLP in deep learning.
因此，你可以将NMT称为NLP深度学习的最大成功故事。
Uh, because if you think about the history of this,
呃，因为如果你想一想这个的历史，
NMT went from being a fringe research activity in 2014 to being actually
NMT从2014年的边缘研究活动变为实际
the leading standard methodfor machine translation in the world in 2016.
2016年全球机器翻译的领先标准方法。
In particular, in 2014,
特别是在2014年，
the first seq2seq paper was published.
第一篇seq2seq论文发表。
And in 2016, Google Translate switches from SMT to NMT.
2016年，谷歌翻译从SMT切换到NMT。
This is a pretty remarkable turnaround for just two years.
这是一个非常显着的转变仅仅两年。
So this is amazing,
所以这太棒了，
not just because it was a quick turnaround,
不只是因为它是一个快速的转变，
but also if you think about the level of human effort involved.
但是如果你考虑到人类努力程度的话。
Uh, these SMT systems, for example
呃，这些SMT系统，例如
the Google Translate SMT system was built by
谷歌翻译SMT系统是由
doubtless hundreds of engineers over many years.
多年来无疑是数百名工程师。
And this, uh, this SMT system was outperformed by an NMT system that was trained by,
而且，呃，这个SMT系统的性能优于受过以下培训的NMT系统，
uh, you know, relatively few like a handful of engineers in a few months.
呃，你知道，几个月内几乎没有几个工程师。
So I'm not- I'm not diminishing how difficult it is to,
所以我不是 - 我没有减少它的难度，
um, build NMT systems,
嗯，建立NMT系统，
and certainly I'm sure Google's NMT system
当然我肯定谷歌的NMT系统
today is built by more than a handful of engineers in a few months.
今天是由几个月内的少数工程师建造的。
I'm sure it's a very big operation now.
我相信现在这是一个非常大的操作。
Uh, but when NMT,
呃，但是当NMT，
uh, began to outperform SMT,
呃，开始超越SMT，
it was pretty remarkable how it was able to do that,
如何能够做到这一点非常了不起，
uh, based on the amount of effort involved. Yeah.
呃，基于所涉及的努力量。是啊。
Given the [inaudible] cons of NMT has there been research on  combining the two and if there is, what does that look like?
鉴于NMT的[听不清]缺点，有关于两者结合的研究，如果有的话，那看起来是什么样的？
Yeah, great. The question is given that we know that there are
很好。问题是我们知道有
some disadvantages of NMT even in comparison to SMT,
与SMT相比，NMT的一些缺点，
is there any work on combining the two?
是否有任何合并两者的工作？
So, yes. I think there is.
所以，是的。我觉得有。
Uh, there's a lot of NMT research ongoing and in particular,
呃，正在进行大量的NMT研究，特别是
people sometimes focus on these particular shortcomings.
人们有时会关注这些特殊的缺点。
And, uh, there's a lot of work in kind of taking techniques
而且，呃，有很多工作采取技术
and ideas and wisdom from the many decades of SMT research,
几十年的SMT研究中的思想和智慧，
and then integrating them into the new NMT paradigm.
然后将它们整合到新的NMT范例中。
So yes. [NOISE]. Okay.
是的[噪声]。好的。
So is machine translation solved?
机器翻译解决了吗？
Can we all go home? I think the answer is clearly no.
我们都可以回家吗？我认为答案显然不是。
Uh, NMT definitely is not doing machine translation perfectly.
呃，NMT肯定不是完美的机器翻译。
So, um, just to highlight some of the difficulties that remained with NMT.
所以，嗯，只是为了强调NMT仍然存在的一些困难。
Uh, one is out-of-vocabulary words.
呃，一个是词汇外的单词。
Uh, this is a kind of basic problem but it is pretty tricky.
呃，这是一个基本的问题，但它非常棘手。
You know, what do you do if you're trying to translate
你知道，如果你想翻译，你会怎么做？
a sentence that contains a word that is not in your source vocabulary,
包含不在源词汇表中的单词的句子，
or what if you're trying to produce a word that's not in your target vocabulary?
或者如果你试图产生一个不在你的目标词汇中的单词怎么办？
Um, there's certainly been lots of work on doing this,
嗯，这方面肯定有很多工作要做，
and you're going to hear later in the class how you
你会在课堂上听到你的意见
might try to attack this with for example,
可能试图用例如攻击这个，
uh, sub-word modeling can make it easier.
呃，子词建模可以使它更容易。
Uh, but this is a significant problem.
呃，但这是一个重大问题。
Another one is domain mismatch.
另一个是域名不匹配。
So let's suppose that you train your machine translation system on a bunch of fairly,
所以我们假设您在一堆公平的情况下培训您的机器翻译系统，
uh, formal text, like let's say,
呃，正式文本，就像我们说的那样，
uh, Wikipedia or something like that.
呃，维基百科或类似的东西。
Uh, but then you try to deploy it to translate
呃，但是你试着将它部署到翻译
informal text, like people chatting on Twitter or something.
非正式文本，就像在Twitter上聊天的人一样。
Then often, you'll find that it doesn't perform very well
然后经常，你会发现它表现不佳
on this different domain because you've got a domain mismatch.
在这个不同的域上，因为你有一个域不匹配。
Uh, so that's quite a big problem.
呃，这是一个很大的问题。
Another one is maintaining context over longer text.
另一个是保持较长文本的上下文。
So everything we've talked about so far has assumed that you were
所以我们到目前为止所谈论的一切都假设你是
just translating a single sentence to a single sentence,
只是将一个句子翻译成一个句子，
and there's no other wider context.
而且没有其他更广泛的背景。
Uh, but, you know if you want to use
呃，但是，你知道你是否想要使用
a machine translation system to translate a whole news article and maybe even a book,
翻译整个新闻文章甚至书籍的机器翻译系统，
then you're probably going to want to use the context that came in
然后你可能会想要使用进来的上下文
previous sentences in order to translate things correctly in the current sentence.
以前的句子，以便在当前句子中正确翻译。
So, uh, this is an active area of research,
所以，呃，这是一个活跃的研究领域，
how can you get an NMT system to condition on
你如何让NMT系统成为现实
larger pieces of context without it becoming too expensive and so on?
更大的背景而不会变得太昂贵等等？
Another difficulty is low-resource language pairs.
另一个困难是低资源语言对。
Um, everything we've talked about so far has assumed that you have
嗯，到目前为止我们所谈论的一切都假设你有
access to a very large parallel corpus, but what if you don't?
访问一个非常大的平行语料库，但如果你不这样做呢？
What if you are trying to translate to or from a language that
如果您尝试翻译或使用某种语言，该怎么办？
has relatively little text available,
可用的文字相对较少，
um, online for example?
嗯，在网上举个例子？
So that can be pretty difficult.
所以这可能非常困难。
Here a few examples of machine translation screwing up,
这里有一些机器翻译搞砸的例子，
uh, with specific errors.
呃，有特定的错误。
So, here's an example of how common sense is really difficult for NMT systems.
所以，这是NMT系统常识难以实现的一个例子。
On the left, we have the English phrase paper jam,
在左边，我们有英文短语卡纸，
which means when your printer
这意味着你的打印机
gets jammed up with paper and it's all, uh, tangled inside.
被纸张堵住，这就是全部，呃，纠缠在里面。
And then on the right,
然后在右边，
we have a very literal translation of that into Spanish,
我们有一个非常直译的西班牙语，
and it's essentially saying jam,
它本质上是说堵塞，
edible jam made of paper,
由纸制成的可食用果酱，
which clearly isn't the right interpretation.
这显然不是正确的解释。
So here, we have an NMT system that's just doing
所以在这里，我们有一个正在做的NMT系统
very literal translation and clearly doesn't have any notion of common sense.
非常字面的翻译，显然没有任何常识的概念。
You can't make jam from paper. Uh, here's another example.
你不能用纸制作果酱。呃，这是另一个例子。
NMT can pick up biases in the training data.
NMT可以获取训练数据中的偏差。
We already talked about this at the,
我们已经在讨论了这个问题，
uh, the word embedding level,
呃，嵌入级别，
the representation of words.
单词的表示。
Uh, but it can also be a problem at the you know,
呃，但是你知道它也可能是一个问题，
the sentence level when you're translating things.
翻译事物时的句子级别。
So here in this example,
所以在这个例子中，
uh, on the left,
呃，在左边，
we have two sentences in Malay that roughly mean,
我们在马来语中有两个句子大致意思是，
uh, they work as a nurse, and they work as a programmer.
呃，他们是一名护士，他们是一名程序员。
The point is on the left,
这一点在左边，
there is no information about gender in the pronouns.
代词中没有关于性别的信息。
But when it gets translated to English,
但当它被翻译成英文时，
then we've suddenly got gender coming out of nowhere,
然后我们突然间突然出现性别，
she works as a nurse, and he works as a programmer.
她是一名护士，他是一名程序员。
This is likely happening because in our training data,
这可能是因为在我们的培训数据中，
we had more examples of female nurses and male programmers.
我们有更多的女护士和男性程序员的例子。
So you can understand why from a machine learning, uh,
所以你可以从机器学习中理解为什么，呃，
maximizing the objective point of view the,
最大化客观的观点，
uh, English language model has learned to do that.
呃，英语语言模型已经学会了这样做。
But the problem here is this isn't good machine translation.
但这里的问题是这不是好机器翻译。
Uh, here the system is making up information that was not present in the source sentence.
呃，这里系统正在编写源句中没有的信息。
So this is certainly an error that
所以这肯定是一个错误
the machine translation shouldn't be doing because it's just simply inaccurate.
机器翻译不应该这样做，因为它只是不准确。
And even worse, it's propagating, uh, gender roles.
更糟糕的是，它正在传播，呃，性别角色。
Here's another pretty weird example.
这是另一个非常奇怪的例子。
[LAUGHTER] What is happening here?
[大笑]这里发生了什么？
Uh, on the left,
呃，在左边，
we have a nonsense sentence,
我们有一个无意义的句子，
this is just kind of a syllable repeated.
这只是一种重复的音节。
And we're supposedly translating from Somali.
我们据说是从索马里翻译的。
Uh, and then we're asking to translate this into
呃，然后我们要求把它翻译成
English and then we're getting this out of nowhere.
英语，然后我们无处不在。
Um, as the name of the Lord was written in the Hebrew language,
嗯，正如耶和华的名字是用希伯来语写的，
it was written in the language of the Hebrew nation,
它是用希伯来民族的语言写成的，
and you might be thinking "Where on earth did that come from?"
而你可能会想到“这究竟来自哪里？”
And in fact, this got reported in the media as you know,
事实上，据媒体报道，你知道，
Google Translate wants to convert you to its religion or whatever.
谷歌翻译希望将你转变为宗教或其他任何东西。
[LAUGHTER] Um, so for sure,
[笑声]嗯，所以可以肯定的是，
it is very startling.
这是非常令人吃惊的。
But the thing is there's actually quite a reasonable explanation.
但问题实际上是非常合理的解释。
So what's going on here is that,
那么这里发生的是，
um, often for low resource languages,
嗯，通常用于低资源语言，
such as for example Somali, um,
例如索马里，嗯，
one of the best resources of parallel text is the Bible.
平行文本的最佳资源之一是圣经。
So you train for example Somali to English using the Bible as a training text,
因此，您使用圣经作为训练文本训练索马里语为英语，
maybe among other texts.
也许在其他文本中。
Okay, that's the first puzzle piece.
好的，那是第一个拼图。
But the other puzzle piece is the nonsensical input.
但另一个难题是无意义的输入。
So when the input isn't really Somali or any kind of text, right?
所以当输入不是真正的索马里或任何一种文本时，对吧？
It's just the same syllable over and over.
它只是一遍又一遍的音节。
Then the NMT system doesn't really have anything sensible to condition on.
然后NMT系统真的没有任何明智的条件。
Its basically nonsense, it's just noise.
它基本上是胡说八道，只是噪音。
So what does the NMT system do?
那NMT系统做了什么？
Right? It can't really use, it can't really  condition on the source sentence.
对？它无法真正使用，它无法真正对源语句进行条件限制。
So what it does, is it just uses the English language model, right?
它的作用是什么，它只是使用英语模型，对吗？
You can think of it as like the English language model of the decoder RNN
您可以将其视为解码器RNN的英语语言模型
just kind of goes into autopilot and starts generating random text,
只是进入自动驾驶仪并开始生成随机文本，
kind of like we saw last week when we saw, uh,
有点像我们上周看到的那样，呃，
a language model trained on Obama's speeches or
奥巴马演讲或演讲的语言模型
Harry Potter would just generate texts in that style.
哈利波特只会以这种风格生成文本。
That's kind of what's happening here with the Bible,
这就是圣经中发生的事情，
because we don't have any useful information,
因为我们没有任何有用的信息，
um, from the sentence on the left.
嗯，从左边的句子。
Um, so, this is an example why, uh,
嗯，这是一个例子，为什么，呃，
neural machine translation in particular makes these kinds of errors,
特别是神经机器翻译会产生这些错误，
uh, because the system is uninterpretable.
呃，因为系统无法解释。
So you don't know that this is going to happen until it happens,
所以你不知道这种情况会发生，直到它发生，
and perhaps Google didn't know this was going to
也许谷歌不知道这是怎么回事
happen until it happened and it got reported.
发生直到它发生并报告。
Um, so this is one downside of uninterpretability is that really weird effects can
嗯，所以这是一个无法解释的缺点，就是真正奇怪的效果可以
happen and you don't see them coming and it's not
发生了，你没有看到他们来了，事实并非如此
always even easy to explain why they happened. Yeah?
总是很容易解释他们为什么会这样。是吗？
[inaudible].
[听不见的。
Ah, the question is what happens if you did translate from Irish?
啊，问题是如果你从爱尔兰语翻译会发生什么？
I suppose that's the part where Google tries to autodetect
我想这是Google尝试自动检测的部分
the language, maybe it thinks that ag ag ag is more like Irish than Somali,
这种语言，也许它认为ag ag ag更像爱尔兰人而不是索马里人，
[LAUGHTER] I imagine if you did put Irish to English,
[大笑]我想如果你把爱尔兰语用于英语，
there's probably more, uh,
可能还有更多，呃，
training data for Irish to English.
爱尔兰语到英语的培训数据。
So maybe it wouldn't be so Bible-focused.
所以也许它不会那么以圣经为中心。
Um, yeah, and there's a lot of examples of these online where
嗯，是的，这里有很多这些在线的例子
you do different kinds of nonsense syllables in different languages.
你用不同的语言做不同种类的无意义音节。
So there's a lot of, uh, challenges remaining in NMT.
所以NMT还有很多呃挑战。
And, uh, the research continues.
而且，呃，研究还在继续。
So NMT, I think remains one of the flagship tasks for NLP Deep Learning.
所以NMT，我认为仍然是NLP深度学习的旗舰任务之一。
In fact, NMT research has pioneered many of
事实上，NMT研究已经开创了许多领域
the successful innovations of NLP Deep Learning in general.
NLP深度学习的成功创新。
Uh, so today in 2019, uh,
呃，今天是2019年，呃，
NMT research continues to thrive, there's still many,
NMT研究继续蓬勃发展，还有很多，
many papers, uh, published all the time on NMT.
许多论文，呃，一直在NMT上发表。
And in fact, uh, researchers have found lots of
事实上，呃，研究人员发现了很多
improvements to the fairly vanilla seq2seq models that I've shown you today.
我今天向您展示的相当香草的seq2seq模型的改进。
Uh, but in fact,
呃，但事实上，
there is one improvement that is so integral
有一个改进是如此不可或缺的
to seq2seq that you could regard it as the new vanilla.
到seq2seq，你可以把它当作新的香草。
And that's the improvement we're going to learn about today,
这就是我们今天要学到的改进，
and it's called attention.
它被称为关注。
Okay. So section three is on attention. What is attention?
好的。所以第三节正在引起关注。什么是关注？
First, I'm going to motivate why we need this thing called attention.
首先，我要激励为什么我们需要这个叫注意的东西。
So let's look at this diagram that we saw before of sequence-to-sequence.
那么让我们看一下我们在序列到序列之前看到的这个图。
And remember when we assumed that this,
记得当我们假设这个时，
uh, encoding of the source sentence,
呃，源句的编码，
the, t he one in the orange box is going to represent the whole sentence.
橙色框中的一个将代表整个句子。
Uh, can anyone volunteer a problem you can see with this architecture?
呃，任何人都可以自愿提出这个架构可以看到的问题吗？
In particular perhaps, a problem with this idea that that single vector is
特别是，这个想法可能存在单个向量的问题
the encoding of the source sentence. Yeah?
源句的编码。是吗？
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Okay, so the answer is something like, um, you're only looking at
好吧，所以答案是这样的，嗯，你只是在看
one word, you mean like the last word in the source sentence?
一句话，你的意思就像源句中的最后一个字？
And you're not seeing more information.
你没有看到更多的信息。
Yeah some- it's, it's something like that.
是的，它就是这样的。
Any other ideas? Yep.
还有其他想法吗？是的。
We might have lost information in
我们可能已经丢失了信息
the beginning of the sentence by the time you get to the end.
到达结束时句子的开头。
Yeah. You might have lost information from [NOISE] the beginning of the sentence by,
是啊。您可能在句子开头[NOISE]丢失了信息，
by the time you get to the end, especially if it was longer than four words.
到你结束的时候，特别是如果它超过四个字。
Right. I think these are different ways of saying a
对。我认为这些是说不同的方式
similar idea [NOISE] which is that we have a kind of informational bottleneck.
类似的想法[NOISE]，这是我们有一种信息瓶颈。
Uh, we're forcing all of the information about the source sentence to be captured
呃，我们强制要捕获关于源句的所有信息
in this single vector because that's the only thing that gets given to the decoder.
在这个单一的向量中，因为这是唯一被赋予解码器的东西。
If some information about source sentence isn't in our vector,
如果有关源句的某些信息不在我们的向量中，
then there's no way the decoder is gonna be able to translate it correctly.
那么解码器就无法正确翻译它。
So this is the, yeah,
所以这就是，是的，
this is an informational bottleneck.
这是一个信息瓶颈。
[NOISE] It's putting kind of too much pressure on
[NOISE]这会给你带来太大的压力
this single vector to be a good representation [NOISE] of the encoder.
这个单一矢量是编码器的良好表示[NOISE]。
So this is the motivation for attention.
所以这是引起注意的动力。
Attention is a neural technique and it provides a solution to the bottleneck problem.
注意力是一种神经技术，它为瓶颈问题提供了解决方案。
The core idea is that on each step [NOISE] of the decoder,
核心思想是解码器的每一步[NOISE]，
you're gonna use a direct connection to the encoder
你将使用与编码器的直接连接
to focus on a particular part of the source sequence.
专注于源序列的特定部分。
So first I'm gonna show you what attention is
首先，我要告诉你注意力是什么
via a diagram so that's kind of an intuitive explanation.
通过图表，这是一种直观的解释。
And then I'm gonna show you the equations later.
然后我会告诉你方程式。
So here's how seq- sequence-to-sequence with attention works.
所以这里是seq-序列到序列的注意力如何工作。
So on the first step of our decoder,
那么在解码器的第一步，
uh, we have our first decoder hidden state.
呃，我们有第一个解码器隐藏状态。
So what we do, is we take the dot-product between
所以我们做的是，我们采取点之间的产品
that decoder hidden state and the first [NOISE] encoder hidden state.
解码器隐藏状态和第一个[NOISE]编码器隐藏状态。
And then we get something called
然后我们得到了一些东西
an attention score which I'm representing by a dot. So that's a scalar.
一个注意分数，我用点代表。这是一个标量。
[NOISE] And in fact,
[NOISE]事实上，
we take the dot-product between the decoder hidden state
我们采用解码器隐藏状态之间的点积
and all of the encoder hidden states.
和所有编码器隐藏状态。
So this means that we get one attention score or one scalar for each of these,
所以这意味着我们每个都得到一个注意力得分或一个标量，
uh, source words effectively.
呃，有效地说出来的话。
So next what we do, is we take those four number scores and we apply the softmax,
接下来我们做的是，我们采用这四个数字得分，我们应用softmax，
uh, distribution, uh, the softmax function to
呃，分配，呃，softmax功能
them and then we get a probability distribution.
然后我们得到一个概率分布。
So here, I'm going to represent that probability distribution as a bar chart.
所以在这里，我将把概率分布表示为条形图。
Um, and we call this the attention distribution and this one sums up to 1.
嗯，我们称之为注意力分布，这个总和为1。
So here, you can see that most of the probability mass is on the first word.
所以在这里，您可以看到大多数概率质量都在第一个单词上。
And that kinda makes sense because our first word essentially means "he" and,
这有点意义，因为我们的第一个字基本上意味着“他”，
uh, were gonna be producing the word "he" first in our target sentence.
呃，在我们的目标句子中首先要生成“他”这个词。
So once we've got this attention distribution,
所以一旦我们得到了这种关注分布，
uh, we're going to use it to produce something called the attention output.
呃，我们将用它来产生一种称为注意力输出的东西。
So the idea is that the attention output is a weighted sum of
所以这个想法是注意力输出是加权和
the encoder hidden states and the weighting is the attention distribution.
编码器隐藏状态和加权是注意分布。
So I've got these dotted arrows that go from
所以我有这些虚线箭头
the attention distribution to the attention output,
关注分布到注意力输出，
probably there should be dotted arrows also from
可能还应该有点箭头
the encoder RNN but that's hard to depict.
编码器RNN，但很难描述。
[NOISE] But the idea is that you're summing up these encoder RNN, uh,
[NOISE]但是这个想法是你在总结这些编码器RNN，呃，
hidden states, [NOISE] but you're gonna weight each
隐藏的状态，[NOISE]，但你会减肥
one according to how much attention distribution it has on them.
一个根据它对它们的注意力分布。
So this means that your attention output which is a single vector is going to be
所以这意味着您的注意力输出将是一个单一的向量
mostly containing information from the hidden states that had high attention.
主要包含隐藏状态的信息，这些信息受到高度关注。
In this case, it's gonna be mostly information from the first hidden state.
在这种情况下，它将主要来自第一个隐藏状态的信息。
So after you do this,
所以你这样做之后
you're going to use the attention output to influence your prediction of the next word.
你将使用注意力输出来影响你对下一个词的预测。
So what you usually do is you concatenate
所以你通常做的就是连接
the attention output with your decoder hidden state and then,
关注输出与您的解码器隐藏状态然后，
uh, use that kind of concatenated pair in the way
呃，在路上使用那种级联对
you would have used the decoder [NOISE] hidden state alone before.
你之前会单独使用解码器[NOISE]隐藏状态。
So that way you can get your probability distribution,
这样你就可以获得概率分布，
uh, y hat 1 of what's coming next.
呃，接下来会发生什么。
So as before, we can use that to sample your next word.
和以前一样，我们可以用它来抽样你的下一个单词。
[NOISE] So on the next step,
[NOISE]所以在下一步，
you just do the same thing again.
你只是再做同样的事情。
You've got your second decoder hidden state.
你有第二个解码器隐藏状态。
Again, you take dot-product with all of the encoder hidden states.
再次，您将带有所有编码器隐藏状态的点积。
You take softmax over that to the get attention distribution.
你可以通过softmax获得注意力分配。
And here, you can see the attention distribution is different.
在这里，你可以看到注意力分布是不同的。
We're putting more attention on, uh, the,
我们正在更加关注，呃，
the word entarté because we're about to produce the word hit.
entarté这个词，因为我们即将产生命中这个词。
Uh, but we're also attending a little bit to
呃，但我们也参加了一些
the second word a because that's telling us that hit is a past tense.
第二个词是因为那告诉我们命中是过去式。
So a cool thing that's happening here is we're getting [NOISE] a soft alignment.
所以这里发生的一件很酷的事情就是让我们的[NOISE]柔和对齐。
If you remember when we looked at alignment in SMT systems,
如果你还记得我们在SMT系统中查看对齐的时候，
it was mostly this, uh,
主要是这个，呃，
hard binary thing with on or off, either these words are aligned or they're not.
打开或关闭硬二进制的东西，这些单词是对齐的还是它们不对齐。
Here, you have a much more flexible soft notion of alignments where,
在这里，你有一个更加灵活的对齐软概念，其中，
uh, each word kind of has a distribution over
呃，每个词都有分布
the corresponding words in the source sentence.
源句中的相应单词。
So another thing to note kind of a side note,
另外要注意的是旁注，
is that sometimes, uh,
有时候，呃，
we take the attention output from the previous hidden state, uh,
我们把前一个隐藏状态的注意力输出，呃，
and we kind of feed it into the decoder again along with the usual word.
我们将它与通常的词一起再次送入解码器。
So that would mean you take the attention output from the first step and kind of
所以这意味着你从第一步开始注意力输出
concatenate it to the word vector for he and then use it in the decoder.
将它连接到他的单词vector，然后在解码器中使用它。
Uh, the reason for this is sometimes it's useful to have this, uh,
呃，这个的原因有时候这个有用，呃，
information from the, the attention on the previous step on the next step.
来自的信息，关注下一步的上一步。
So I'm telling you this because this is something we do in Assignment 4
所以我告诉你这是因为这是我们在作业4中所做的
and it's a fairly common technique but also sometimes people don't do it.
这是一种相当常见的技术，但有时人们却不这样做。
Okay. So, um, the theory is,
好的。所以，嗯，理论是，
that you just do this attention,
那你只是注意了，
uh, computation on every step.
呃，每一步的计算。
And on each step, you're going to be attending to different things.
在每一步，你将会参加不同的事情。
So in our example on this third step,
所以在我们这第三步的例子中，
we look at m' which means me when we
我们看看m'，这意味着我
produce me and then on the last
生产我，然后在最后
three [NOISE] we're probably mostly just gonna be looking at this,
三个[NOISE]我们大概只是要看这个，
uh, fertile word entarté to produce hit me with a pie.
呃，生产的肥沃的词entarté用馅饼打我。
[NOISE] I'm gonna keep going because we don't have a lot of time.
[NOISE]我会继续前进，因为我们没有很多时间。
Uh, so here are the equations to describe attention.
呃，所以这里有描述注意力的方程式。
Uh, I think it's probably easier to look at these in
呃，我觉得看看这些可能更容易
your own time later rather than look at them in the lecture now.
你自己的时间，而不是现在在讲座中看他们。
But these are the equations that essentially
但这些是基本上的方程式
say the same thing as what the diagram just said.
说出与图中所说的相同的东西。
So you have your encoder hidden states h_1 up to h_N.
所以你的编码器隐藏状态h_1高达h_N。
And then on timestep t of the decoder,
然后在解码器的时间步长，
we also have a decoder hidden state, uh, S_t.
我们还有一个解码器隐藏状态，呃，S_t。
So we're gonna get the attention score which we're gonna call et by taking
因此，我们将得到我们将要采取的注意力得分
the dot-product of your decoder hidden state with each of the encoder hidden states.
解码器隐藏状态的点积与每个编码器隐藏状态。
[NOISE] And that gives you, uh,
[NOISE]这会给你，呃，
a vector of same length as the, uh,
一个与呃相同长度的向量，
encoder [NOISE] sentence because you've got one score per source word.
编码器[NOISE]句子，因为每个源词有一个分数。
Next you take softmax over these scores
接下来，你将softmax超过这些分数
to get attention distribution that sums up to 1,
获得总计达1的注意力分配，
and we call that alpha.
我们称之为alpha。
And then you use alpha to take a weighted sum of
然后你使用alpha来获取加权和
the encoder hidden states and that gives you your attention output.
编码器隐藏状态，并提供您的注意力输出。
So [NOISE] the attention output which we call a is a vector that's
所以[NOISE]我们称之为a的注意力输出是一个向量
the same size as your encoder hidden states.
与编码器隐藏状态大小相同。
Lastly, you take your attention output a and then you, [NOISE] uh,
最后，你把你的注意力输出a然后你，[NOISE]呃，
concatenate it with your decoder hidden states and then
然后将它与解码器隐藏状态连接起来
proceed with that as you were taught before in the no attention model.
正如你之前在无注意模型中所教导的那样继续。
So attention, if it's not clear, it's pretty cool.
所以注意，如果不清楚的话，这很酷。
It has a number of advantages.
它有许多优点。
So one advantage is that attention just significantly improves NMT performance.
因此，一个优点是注意力可以显着提高NMT的性能。
And the main reason why it improves it,
它改善它的主要原因，
is because it turns out it's super useful to allow the decoder [NOISE] to
是因为事实证明，允许解码器[NOISE]是非常有用的
focus on certain parts of the source sentence when it's translating.
在翻译时，关注源句的某些部分。
And you can see why this makes sense, right?
你可以看出为什么这是有道理的，对吧？
Because there's a very natural notion of alignment,
因为有一种非常自然的对齐概念，
and if you can focus on the specific word or words you're translating,
如果您可以专注于您正在翻译的特定单词或单词，
you can probably do a better job.
你可以做得更好。
Another reason why attention is cool is that [NOISE] it solves the bottleneck problem.
注意力很酷的另一个原因是[NOISE]它解决了瓶颈问题。
Uh, we were noting that the problem with having
呃，我们注意到了问题
a single vector that has to represent the entire source sentence [NOISE] and that's
一个向量，必须代表整个源句[NOISE]，那就是
the only way information can pass from encoder to decoder
信息可以从编码器传递到解码器的唯一方式
means that if that encoding isn't very good then, uh, you're not gonna do well.
意味着，如果那个编码不是很好，那么，呃，你不会做得好。
So by contrast in, uh, with attention,
相比之下，呃，注意力，
the decoder can look directly at the encoder and
解码器可以直接查看编码器和
the source sentence and translate without the bottleneck.
源句和翻译没有瓶颈。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Another great thing about attention is that it helps with the vanishing gradient problem,
注意力的另一个好处是它有助于消除梯度问题，
especially if your sentences are quite long.
特别是如果你的句子很长。
Uh, the reason why attention helps is because you have
呃，注意力有帮助的原因是因为你有
these direct connections between the decoder and the encoder,
解码器和编码器之间的这些直接连接，
kind of over many time steps.
多种时间步骤。
So it's like a shortcut connection.
所以它就像一个快捷方式连接。
And just as we learned last time about, uh,
正如我们上次了解到的那样，呃，
skip connections being [NOISE] useful for reducing vanishing gradient.
跳过连接[NOISE]有助于减少消失的梯度。
Here it's the same notion.
这是相同的概念。
We have these, uh, long distance
我们有这些，呃，长距离
[NOISE] direct connections that help the gradients flow better.
[NOISE]直接连接，有助于梯度更好地流动。
Another great thing about attention is it provides some interpretability.
关注的另一个好处是它提供了一些可解释性。
Uh, if you look at the attention distribution,
呃，如果看一下注意力分布，
often you've produced your translation.
通常你已经制作了翻译。
Uh, you can see what the decoder was focusing on on each step.
呃，你可以看到解码器在每一步都关注的是什么。
So for example if we run our system and we translate our,
所以，例如，如果我们运行我们的系统，我们翻译我们的，
our running example here,
我们这里运行的例子，
then we can produce a plot,
然后我们可以制作一个情节，
kind of like this that shows the attention distribution.
有点像这样显示了注意力的分布。
So here, dark means high attention and white means low attention.
所以在这里，黑暗意味着高度关注，白色意味着低关注。
So you might see something like this where,
所以你可能会看到这样的东西，
um, it was, it was focusing on the different words and different steps.
嗯，它是，它专注于不同的单词和不同的步骤。
And this is basically the same kind of
这基本上是相同的
plot that we had earlier with a hard notion of alignment,
我们之前有一个难以对齐的概念的情节，
uh, in SNT except that we, uh,
呃，在SNT，除了我们，呃，
we have more flexibility to have a more soft version of alignment
我们可以更灵活地使用更柔和的对齐版本
like for example when we produce the English word hit,
例如，当我们生成英文单词hit时，
perhaps we were mostly looking at entarte, but we're also looking at a little bit of A.
也许我们主要看的是entarte，但我们也在考虑一点A.
So this, uh, means that we're getting,
所以，这，呃，意味着我们得到了，
uh, alignment for free.
呃，免费对齐。
And the reason I say for free is because when you remember the SNT systems,
我免费说的原因是因为当你记得SNT系统时，
the whole point there is that you had to learn
总的来说，你必须要学习
an alignment system deliberately and separately.
故意和分开地对准系统。
You had to define the notion of alignment,
你必须定义对齐的概念，
you had to define the model of calculating,
你必须定义计算模型，
what the probability of different alignments were and train it.
不同路线的概率是多少，并训练它。
Whereas here, we never told the NMT system about alignments.
在这里，我们从未告诉NMT系统有关对齐。
We never explicitly trained an alignment system.
我们从未明确培训过校准系统。
We never had a loss function that tells you how good your alignment was.
我们从未有过一个能够告诉你对齐有多好的损失函数。
We just gave the NMT system the apparatus to
我们刚给了NMT系统设备
do something like alignments and told it to maximize the,
做一些像对齐，告诉它最大化，
uh, the cross-entropy loss for doing machine translation.
呃，机器翻译的交叉熵损失。
And then the network just learned alignment by itself.
然后网络本身就学会了对齐。
I think this is the coolest thing about attention,
我认为这是关注最酷的事情，
is that it's learned some structure in a somewhat unsupervised way.
是因为它以某种无人监督的方式学习了一些结构。
Okay, so in the last few minutes,
好的，所以在最后几分钟，
I'm just going to, uh, generalize the notion of attention.
我只是想，呃，概括一下注意力的概念。
Because it turns out that attention is actually a very general, uh,
因为事实证明注意力实际上是非常普遍的，呃，
deep learning technique that you can apply in lots of different circumstances.
深度学习技巧，你可以在很多不同的情况下应用。
So you've seen that attention is a great way to improve
所以你已经看到注意力是改善的好方法
the sequence-to-sequence model for MT,
MT的序列到序列模型，
but you can actually use attention for other architectures that aren't
但实际上，您可以将注意力集中用于其他非体系结构
seq2seq and also tasks that aren't MT.
seq2seq以及非MT的任务。
So to understand this,
所以要理解这一点，
I'm going to somewhat redefine attention to a more general definition.
我将在某种程度上重新关注更普遍的定义。
So here's our more general definition.
所以这是我们更一般的定义。
Suppose you have a set of values,
假设你有一组值，
each of which is a vector,
每个都是矢量，
and you also have a single vector in which you're calling the query.
并且您还有一个向量，您可以在其中调用查询。
Then attention is a way, uh,
然后注意是一种方式，呃，
to compute a weighted sum of the values.
计算值的加权和。
But the way you weight it is dependent on the query.
但你加权的方式取决于查询。
[NOISE] So we often phrase this,
[NOISE]所以我们经常说这个，
uh, as saying that the query is attending to the values.
呃，说查询是关注值的。
The idea being that you have all this information that's in the values and
这个想法是你拥有价值观和价值观中的所有信息
the query is somehow determining how it's going to pay attention to the values.
查询以某种方式确定它将如何关注值。
So for example in seq2seq, uh,
所以例如在seq2seq，呃，
the decoder hidden state is the query.
解码器隐藏状态是查询。
Uh the decoder hidden state on a particular time step is the query
呃，特定时间步骤的解码器隐藏状态是查询
and is attending to all the encoder hidden states which are the values.
并且正在关注作为值的所有编码器隐藏状态。
All right, here's our definition again.
好的，这是我们的定义。
So here's a way to kind of understand this intuitively, two alternative ways.
所以这是一种直观地理解这种方式的两种方式。
One is to think of it like this.
一个是这样想的。
You could think of it as the weighted sum is like
您可以将其视为加权和就像
a selective summary of the information in the values.
有价值信息的选择性摘要。
And I say selective because your choice of how much you choose
我说有选择性因为你选择了多少
to draw from each value depends on the attention distribution.
从每个值中抽取取决于注意力分布。
Uh, so the distribution, uh, depends on the query.
呃，所以分发，呃，取决于查询。
So the query is determining how much you're going to select from different, uh, values.
因此查询确定您将从不同的值中选择多少值。
And this is kind of similar to LSTM that learned about earlier this week.
这有点类似于本周早些时候了解到的LSTM。
LSTMs rule based on the idea of a gate that, uh,
LSTM基于门的概念来统治，呃，
[NOISE] that defines how much information shou-
[NOISE]定义了多少信息 -
should [NOISE] come from different elements.
应该[噪音]来自不同的元素。
And the gate depends on the context.
大门取决于背景。
So the strength of LSTMs came from the idea that based on the context,
因此，LSTM的优势来自于基于背景的观点，
you decide where you're going to draw information from.
你决定从哪里提取信息。
And this is kind of like the same idea.
这有点像同样的想法。
The second way to think about attention is you could say that it's a way to obtain
考虑注意力的第二种方式是你可以说它是一种获得方式
a fixed-size representation from an arbitrary set of representations.
来自任意一组表示的固定大小表示。
So when I say arbitrary sets,
所以当我说任意组时，
I'm saying we have this set of vectors called the values, right?
我说我们有这组称为值的向量，对吧？
And you could have 10 values.
你可以有10个值。
You could have 100 values.
你可以有100个值。
You can have, uh,
你可以拥有，呃，
any [NOISE] arbitrary number of these vectors.
任何[NOISE]任意数量的这些向量。
But attention gives you a way to get a single vector,
但注意力为你提供了获得单个矢量的方法，
um, summary of that which is the attention output, uh, using your query.
嗯，使用您的查询，注意输出的总结，呃。
Okay, uh, so the last thing, uh,
好的，呃，最后一件事，呃，
is that there's actually several variants of
实际上有几种变体
attention and this is something were are going to look at a little in Assignment 4.
注意，这是分配4中的一些内容。
So in our more general setting,
所以在我们更一般的环境中，
we've seen that we have some values in the query.
我们已经看到我们在查询中有一些值。
Doing attention always involves computing the attention [NOISE] scores,
注意力总是涉及计算注意力[NOISE]得分，
and then you apply softmax to get the attention distribution.
然后你应用softmax来获得注意力分配。
And then you use that attention distribution to take a weighted sum.
然后你使用该注意力分布来加权。
So this is, uh, always the outline of how attention works.
所以这就是，呃，总是注意力如何运作的轮廓。
The part that can be different is this, uh, number one.
可能不同的部分是这个，呃，第一。
There are multiple ways you can compute the scores.
您可以通过多种方式计算分数。
So, uh, last slide,
那么，呃，最后一张幻灯片，
here all the different ways you can repeat the scores.
这里有所有不同的方法可以重复分数。
So the first one which you've already seen today is basic dot-product attention.
所以你今天看到的第一个是基本的点产品关注。
And the idea here is that [NOISE] the score for a particular, a particular value,
这里的想法是[NOISE]特定值，特定值的得分，
HI, is just the dot-product of the query and that particular value.
HI，只是查询和特定值的点积。
[NOISE] And, uh, in particular this assumes that the size
[NOISE]而且，呃，特别是这个假设的大小
of your query vector and the size of
您的查询向量和大小
your value vector has to be the same because you're taking dot-product.
你的价值向量必须相同，因为你正在使用点积。
[NOISE] Another, uh, version of,
[NOISE]另一个，呃，版本的，
uh, attention is called multiplicative attention.
呃，注意力被称为乘法注意力。
And here, the idea is that the score of your, uh,
在这里，这个想法是你的得分，呃，
value HI, is going to be this, uh,
价值HI，将是这个，呃，
bi-linear function of your query and that value.
查询和该值的双线性函数。
So in particular, we're pushing this weight matrix in
所以特别是，我们正在推动这个权重矩阵
the middle and that's a learnable parameter.
中间，这是一个可学习的参数。
You're learning the best way matric- ma- weight matrix in order to get the scores,
你正在学习基质矩阵的最佳方法来获得分数，
the attention scores that are useful.
有用的注意力得分。
The last one is called additive attention.
最后一个被称为加性注意。
So what's happening here is that the score of the value HI is, uh,
那么这里发生的是HI值的得分是，呃，
you get it by applying
你通过申请得到它
a linear transformation to both the value and the query and then you add them together.
对值和查询进行线性转换，然后将它们一起添加。
And then you put them through a non-linearity like tanh.
然后你把它们放在像tanh这样的非线性中。
And then lastly, uh,
最后，呃，
you take that vector and you take the dot-product with
你拿那个矢量，你拿点产品
a weight vector to give you a single number that is the score.
一个权重向量，给你一个分数的数字。
[NOISE] So here, you've got
[NOISE]所以在这里，你有
two different weight matrices and [NOISE]
两种不同的权重矩阵和[NOISE]
also a weight vector which are the learnable parameters.
也是一个可学习参数的权重向量。
One thing that's different here is that there's kind of an additional hyperparameter,
这里有一点不同的是，还有一种额外的超参数，
which is the attention dimensionality.
这是注意维度。
So [NOISE] that's kind of, uh, the,
所以[NOISE]那是什么，呃，
I think it's the heights of the W1 and W2 and this is the length of V, right?
我认为它是W1和W2的高度，这是V的长度，对吗？
You can choose what size that dimension is.
您可以选择尺寸的大小。
It's kind of like a hidden layer in the computation.
它有点像计算中的隐藏层。
So, um, you can decide how big you want that intermediate representation to be.
所以，嗯，你可以决定你想要多大的中间表示。
Okay, so I'm not going to tell you any more about that because that's
好的，所以我不会再告诉你了，因为那是
actually one of the questions in the assignment, uh,
实际上是作业中的一个问题，呃，
Assignment 4 is to think about
作业4是要考虑的
the relative advantages and disadvantages of these models.
这些模型的相对优缺点。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So here's a summary of today.
所以这是今天的总结。
[NOISE] It really is the last slide,
[NOISE]这真的是最后一张幻灯片，
[BACKGROUND] second last, last time,
[背景]倒数第二次，最后一次，
but this was the last slide.
但这是最后一张幻灯片。
[BACKGROUND] So we learned about the history of MT.
[背景]因此我们了解了MT的历史。
[NOISE] We learned about how in 2014 [NOISE] Neural MT revolutionized MT.
[NOISE]我们了解了2014年[NOISE]神经MT如何彻底改变MT。
[NOISE] We learned about how sequence-to-sequence
[NOISE]我们了解了序列到序列的方式
is the right architecture for NMT and it uses two RNNs.
是NMT的正确架构，它使用两个RNN。
And lastly, we learned about how attention [NOISE] is a way to focus
最后，我们了解了注意力[NOISE]是一种集中注意力的方式
on particular parts of the input. All right, thanks.
在输入的特定部分。好的，谢谢。